<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ArrayOfServiceInfo xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/20100205/">
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/czo_udel/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Christina River Basin Critical Zone Observatory</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=163</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>aufdenkampe@stroudcenter.org</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>Stroud Research Center / University of Deleware</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.udel.edu/czo/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>An NSF supported environmental observatory established to study chemical, physical and biological interactions that shape the Earth's surface</citation>
    <aabstract>Spatial and temporal integration of carbon and mineral fluxes: a whole watershed approach to quantifying anthropogenic modification of critical zone carbon sequestration. Earth moving by humans associated with agriculture, urbanization, and excavation re-contours entire landscapes and constitutes a major geological force within the Critical Zone of planet Earth. The Critical Zone, defined as the terrestrial layer extending from tree tops through the groundwater and into stream networks, sustains most terrestrial life on the planet. At a greater rate than ever in Earth’s history, erosion and excavation expose sub-soil materials and unweathered minerals, which mix into and within soils and are transported as sediment loads through river networks, from headwaters to estuaries. To quantify the impacts on the global carbon cycle of humans as geological agents, a multidisciplinary team of scientists from the University of Delaware (UD) and Stroud Water Research Center (SWRC) will establish a Critical Zone Observatory (CZO) within the 1440 km2 Christina River drainage basin (CRB/CZO). Scientific investigations within the CRB/CZO, located in Southeastern Pennsylvania and Northern Delaware and straddling unglaciated Piedmont and Coastal Plain physiographic provinces, will test the following overarching hypothesis: Humans, by accelerating the introduction of minerals into biologically and chemically active zones, significantly enhance the interactions between minerals and organic matter and create globally significant impacts on the exchange of carbon between the land and the atmosphere. The human footprint within the CRB/CZO spans centuries, and current land uses include second-growth forests, agriculture, and suburban and urban development This provides an ideal natural laboratory in which we will investigate fundamental biological, chemical, and geological processes within the Critical Zone along a gradient of human impacts. We will particularly focus on the sources, transport and fates of water, sediments and carbon from uplands to inland waters and from inland waters to the coastal zone. The CRB/CZO will utilize cutting edge technologies for real-time gathering of hydrological, physical and chemical data and advances in cyber-infrastructure that seamlessly merge real-time data with state-of-the-art graphics tools to provide timely open access to quality controlled data and supporting materials. Field installations and data management advances will enhance an extensive existing network of stations used for monitoring water flow and water chemistry within the CRB basin, including Delaware Coastal Waters, and will build upon a solid foundation of decades of research conducted by UD, SWRC, and numerous state, federal, and non-governmental agencies. The CRB/CZO will serve as a resource to the greater scientific community through open access to data and opportunities for research projects that take advantage of the enhanced monitoring network. The new Delaware Environmental Institute (DENIN), located at UD, and Delaware's National Science Foundation Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research (EPSCoR) will partner with the CRB/CZO on outreach activities. Public outreach to stakeholders within the Christina Basin is a critical step in making CRB/CZO data available to policy makers. Strong ties between UD and Delaware state agencies will enhance the sharing of environmental data and will provide outreach to the public and to policy makers. Some of our outreach will be coordinated through the Water Resources Agency, part of the UD Institute for Public Administration. The Christina Basin Water Quality Management Committee, which includes representatives from 15 federal, state, and local environmental resource agencies, hosts an annual series of public workshops to identify the science needs of policy makers. We will incorporate science results from the CRB/CZO into these workshops with the goal of providing a direct interface between science and public policy. The SWRC maintains 4 full-time staff members to translate our research into educational programs for middle- and high school-aged students, teachers, and citizen/conservation groups. Graduate students who are involved with the CRB/CZO will be advised by multidisciplinary team of scientists associated with the DENIN and with scientists at SWRC. Collaborations with other academic and federal agency personnel will further enhance interdisciplinary research, student education, and public outreach.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>21081083</valuecount>
    <variablecount>45</variablecount>
    <sitecount>68</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>163</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>czo_udel</NetworkName>
    <minx>-75.79139</minx>
    <miny>39.8548</miny>
    <maxx>-75.65321</maxx>
    <maxy>39.94947</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydro1.sci.gsfc.nasa.gov/daac-bin/his/1.0/NLDAS_FORA_002.cgi?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>NLDAS Hourly Primary Forcing Data</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=267</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>gsfc-help-disc@lists.nasa.gov</Email>
    <phone>301-614-5224</phone>
    <organization>NASA Goddard Earth Sciences (GES) Data and Information Services Center</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://disc.sci.gsfc.nasa.gov/hydrology/data-holdings</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Mitchell, K.E., D. Lohmann, P.R. Houser, E.F. Wood, J.C. Schaake, A. Robock, B.A. Cosgrove, J. Sheffield, Q. Duan, L. Luo, R.W. Higgins, R.T. Pinker, J.D. Tarpley, D.P. Lettenmaier, C.H. Marshall, J.K. Entin, M. Pan, W. Shi, V. Koren, J. Meng, B. H. Ramsay, and A.A. Bailey (2004), The multi-institution North American Land Data Assimilation System (NLDAS): Utilizing multiple GCIP products and partners in a continental distributed hydrological modeling system, J. Geophys. Res., 109, D07S90, doi:10.1029/2003JD003823.</citation>
    <aabstract>The goal of NLDAS is to construct quality-controlled, and spatially and temporally consistent, land-surface model (LSM) datasets from the best available observations and model output to support modeling activities. Specifically, this system is intended to reduce the errors in the stores of soil moisture and energy which are often present in numerical weather prediction models, and which degrade the accuracy of forecasts. NLDAS is currently running in near real-time on a 1/8th-degree grid over central North America; retrospective NLDAS datasets and simulations also extend back to January 1979. NLDAS constructs a forcing dataset from gauge-based observed precipitation data (temporally disaggregated using Stage II radar data), bias-correcting shortwave radiation, and surface meteorology reanalyses to drive several different LSMs to produce model outputs of surface fluxes, soil moisture, and snow cover. NLDAS is a collaboration project among several groups: NOAA/NCEP's Environmental Modeling Center (EMC), NASA's Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC), Princeton University, the University of Washington, the NOAA/NWS Office of Hydrological Development (OHD), and the NOAA/NCEP Climate Prediction Center (CPC). NLDAS is a core project with support from NOAA's Climate Prediction Program for the Americas (CPPA). Data from the project can be accessed from the NASA Goddard Earth Science Data and Information Services Center (GES DISC) as well as from the NCEP/EMC NLDAS website. This service provides access to NASA's North American Land Data Assimilation System (NLDAS) hourly Mosaic land surface model data.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>2147483647</valuecount>
    <variablecount>5</variablecount>
    <sitecount>103936</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>267</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>NLDAS_FORA</NetworkName>
    <minx>-124.9375</minx>
    <miny>25.0625</miny>
    <maxx>-67.0625</maxx>
    <maxy>52.9375</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydro10.sdsc.edu/gama_saih/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>UPM / GAMA - SAIH network, Spain </Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=283</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email />
    <phone />
    <organization>UPM / GAMA</organization>
    <orgwebsite />
    <citation />
    <aabstract>Continuous monitoring data within the SAIH network collected by the Agència Catalana de l'Aigua,None,Raül Marcos,34 9340 39231,rmarcos@am.ub.es,"Martí i Franquès 1, 7th Floor. Astronomy and Meteorology Department",Barcelona,Spain,08028,Continuous monitoring data within the SAIH network collected by the Agència Catalana de l'Aigua
</aabstract>
    <valuecount>3177765</valuecount>
    <variablecount>7</variablecount>
    <sitecount>16</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>283</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>GAMA_SAIH</NetworkName>
    <minx>2.6042</minx>
    <miny>41.9862</miny>
    <maxx>3.25</maxx>
    <maxy>42.4276</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/glacialridge/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Glacial Ridge Project</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=185</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>philgerla@mail.und.nodak.edu</Email>
    <phone>701-777-3305</phone>
    <organization>University of North Dakota</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.geology.und.nodak.edu/gerla</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Gerla, P., R. Whitaker, and S. Trobec. 2011. Water quality data from Judicial Ditch 66 and vicinity, Glacial Ridge Project, Mentor, Minnesota. GlacialRidge. The Nature Conservancy - Minnesota, North Dakota, and South Dakota Chapter and the University of North Dakota. Data retrieved from CUAHSI HIS on April 25, 2011.</citation>
    <aabstract>In 2000, The Nature Conservancy Minnesota Chapter purchased the 10,000 ha Tilden Farms property near Crookston, northwestern Minnesota. During the following decade, the cultivated and grazed lands that comprised the property were restored to perennial prairie and wetland. These lands are now being turned over to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service for inclusion and management within the Glacial Ridge National Wildlife Refuge. As reconstructed tracts mature, on-going monitoring reveals the changes in water quality, runoff, and groundwater recharge at selected locations.
</aabstract>
    <valuecount>1771</valuecount>
    <variablecount>30</variablecount>
    <sitecount>21</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>185</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>GlacialRidge</NetworkName>
    <minx>-96.32533</minx>
    <miny>47.72691</miny>
    <maxx>-96.26686</maxx>
    <maxy>47.75981</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/nwisdv/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>NWIS Daily Values</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=1</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>help@cuahsi.org</Email>
    <phone>339-221-5400</phone>
    <organization>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS)</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.usgs.gov</orgwebsite>
    <citation>U.S. Geological Survey, [YEAR], National Water Information System data, accessed [DATE ACCESSED] via HIS Central (http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org).                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </citation>
    <aabstract>The USGS National Water Information System (NWIS) provides access to millions of sites measuring streamflow, groundwater levels, and water quality. This web service provides methods for retrieving daily values data, such as discharge and water levels, from NWIS. For more information about NWIS data services, see http://waterservices.usgs.gov/</aabstract>
    <valuecount>393216950</valuecount>
    <variablecount>540</variablecount>
    <sitecount>36057</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>1</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>NWISDV</NetworkName>
    <minx>-999</minx>
    <miny>-999</miny>
    <maxx>179.2467</maxx>
    <maxy>71.29403</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/MOPEX/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>MOPEX</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5599</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>help@cuahsi.org</Email>
    <phone>339-221-5400</phone>
    <organization>NOAA-National Weather Service-Office of Hydrologic Development</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.nws.noaa.gov/ohd/mopex/mo_welcome.htm</orgwebsite>
    <citation>ftp://hydrology.nws.noaa.gov/pub/gcip/mopex/US_Data/Documentation/US%20MOPEX%20Data%20Set%2020060612.pdf</citation>
    <aabstract>The primary goal of MOPEX is to develop techniques for the a priori estimation of the parameters used in land surface parameterization schemes of atmospheric models and in hydrological models. A major early effort of MOPEX has been to assemble a large number of high quality historical hydrometeorlogical and river basin characteristic data sets for a wide range of river basins throughout the world. The HIS catalog holds daily time series data for a few of the many basins. CUAHSI staff downloaded and formatted all time series data.
ftp://hydrology.nws.noaa.gov/pub/gcip/mopex/US_Data/Documentation/US%20MOPEX%20Data%20Set%2020060612.pdf</aabstract>
    <valuecount>18293606</valuecount>
    <variablecount>5</variablecount>
    <sitecount>182</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5599</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>MOPEX</NetworkName>
    <minx>-123.6737</minx>
    <miny>28.29195</miny>
    <maxx>-69.9375</maxx>
    <maxy>48.49552</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/KentState/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL </servURL>
    <Title>Kent State</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5602</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>ajeffer9@kent.edu</Email>
    <phone>330-672-2746</phone>
    <organization>Kent State University</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://all-geo.org/jefferson/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Citation: https://www.scribd.com/document/282989819/Teaching-Isotope-Hydrograph-Separation-with-Real-Data </citation>
    <aabstract>Time series hydrologic and water isotope data were collected in March-April 2014 for the purposes of developing an isotope hydrograph separation for use in teaching. Stream discharge and isotopes were collected from the West Branch of the Mahoning River at Jenning’s Woods, a Kent State University research reserve. The drainage area of the West Branch of the Mahoning River at Jenning’s Woods is 19.6 mi2. Precipitation data are available from a nearby airport weather station and precipitation isotopes were collected on a sub-daily basis in a backyard rain gage in Kent, Ohio, 13 km to the west of the stream. Data collection and teaching exercise development was supported by the National Science Foundation under Grant No. DUE-1140980 and the isotope hydrograph separation exercise is being uploaded to the Science Education Resource Center (http://serc.carleton.edu/index.html). </aabstract>
    <valuecount>2149</valuecount>
    <variablecount>6</variablecount>
    <sitecount>2</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5602</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>ODM_KentState</NetworkName>
    <minx>-81.354</minx>
    <miny>41.156</miny>
    <maxx>-81.2</maxx>
    <maxy>41.174</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/ipswich/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Ipswich River Watershed Association</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=247</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>rodonnell@ipswichriver.org</Email>
    <phone>(978) 412-8200</phone>
    <organization>Ipswich River Watershed Association</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.ipswichriver.org/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Please cite the appropriate monitoring report(s) available at the following website for the timespan of data used:
 
http://ipswich-river.org/resources/monitoring-data/</citation>
    <aabstract>The Ipswich River Watershed Association’s (IRWA) RiverWatch water quality monitoring program, in operation since 1997, enlists volunteers to collect data on the health of the Ipswich River and its tributaries. Volunteers monitor according to a state-approved monitoring plan that ensures that the data they collect is of good quality. The goals of the program are to document River conditions in order to identify water quality problems (including adequate river flow) and to use this data to develop solutions to observed problems.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>11323</valuecount>
    <variablecount>3</variablecount>
    <sitecount>34</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>247</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>IRWA</NetworkName>
    <minx>-71.18291</minx>
    <miny>42.55282</miny>
    <maxx>-70.81902</maxx>
    <maxy>42.69813</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydro10.sdsc.edu/cima1/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>CIMA1</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=258</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>luca.molini@cimafoundation.org</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>CIMA Research Foundation</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.cimafoundation.org</orgwebsite>
    <citation>CIMA research Foundation</citation>
    <aabstract>Historical data, related to the severe rainfall period on NW Italy from 25 October to 05 November 2011, from the Italian Civil Protection Department RAWS network (remotely automated weather stations). The data are provided for research purposes in the framework of the FP7 DRIHM (Distributed Research Infrastructure for Hydro-Meteorology, www.drihm.eu) project.)</aabstract>
    <valuecount>239115</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>839</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>258</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>CIMA1</NetworkName>
    <minx>6.68583</minx>
    <miny>43.55798</miny>
    <maxx>10.49917</maxx>
    <maxy>45.99661</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://143.234.88.22/TarlandHydrologyDataWS/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL </servURL>
    <Title>Tarland Catchment Hydrology Data, Scotland, UK</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=286</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>adekule.ibiyemi@hutton.ac.uk</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>The James Hutton Institute, Aberdeen, Scotland, UK</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.hutton.ac.uk/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Data provided by
The James Hutton Institute
Cragiebuckler, Aberdeen
AB15 8QH
Scotland,UK</citation>
    <aabstract>The data are from the river water processes and qualities monitoring sites being managed by the institute. We do not accept any liability as a result from the use of these data. Please contact us for further information.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>252164</valuecount>
    <variablecount>4</variablecount>
    <sitecount>16</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>286</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>ABHYD01</NetworkName>
    <minx>-2.895416</minx>
    <miny>57.11006</miny>
    <maxx>-2.806031</maxx>
    <maxy>57.15719</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://worldwater.byu.edu/interactive/snotel/services/index.php/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>NRCS SNOTEL Standard Variables</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=241</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jirikadlec2@gmail.com</Email>
    <phone>385-204-2998</phone>
    <organization>Natural Resources Conservation Service</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.wcc.nrcs.usda.gov/snow/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>NRCS, (2012), Data obtained from the NRCS SNOTEL WaterOneFlow web service, Natural Resources Conservation Service.</citation>
    <aabstract>This web service provides access to daily values for the 6 standard variables measured at NRCS SNOTEL sites as published by the NRCS.  These variables include snow water equivalent, precipitation, water year to date precipitation, and daily minimum, maximum, and average air temperature. The web service retrieves data from the NRCS SNOTEL website, formats it as WaterML, and returns it to the user. This web services was developed by Utah State University as part of a National Integrated Drought Information System (NIDIS) project sponsored by the United States Geological Survey.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>55355431</valuecount>
    <variablecount>7</variablecount>
    <sitecount>894</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>241</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>SNOTEL</NetworkName>
    <minx>-164.2926</minx>
    <miny>32.92401</miny>
    <maxx>-103.7876</maxx>
    <maxy>70.26666</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://ariel.lnec.pt/hs/main/services/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>AquaGIS Service</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=3556</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>ncharneca@lnec.pt</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>National Laboratory for Civil Engineering</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.lnec.pt</orgwebsite>
    <citation>AquaGIS-Robotic autonomous platform for surface water monitoring</citation>
    <aabstract>The development of the AquaGIS robotic platform is being done in the scope of a research and development project that aims the construction of an autonomous catamaran vessel for surface water monitoring. The vessel was designed to respond to the European Water Framework Directive (WFD) monitoring programms demands.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>5458995</valuecount>
    <variablecount>46</variablecount>
    <sitecount>4</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>3556</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>aquagis</NetworkName>
    <minx>-9.22193</minx>
    <miny>38.76046</miny>
    <maxx>-9.14358</maxx>
    <maxy>39.42807</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/hassberge/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Hassberge catchment long-Term monitoring data</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=220</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>l.vanschaik@tu-berlin.de</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>Technische University Manchen</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://mds.sommer.at/Web-Service-Admintool/index.php</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Klaus, J., 2011. Preferential flow in a cultivated lower meso-scale catchment: observation, modelling and implications for solute transport. PhD-thesis, Technical University MŸnchen, MŸnchen, Germany.</citation>
    <aabstract>In the Hassberge catchment meteorological and hydrological data have been monitored at a high temporal resolution from 2008 to 2011. This project was funded by Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG), project numbers SCHR 1000/3-1 and ZE 533/5-1.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>899150</valuecount>
    <variablecount>10</variablecount>
    <sitecount>1</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>220</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>Hassberge</NetworkName>
    <minx>10.58601</minx>
    <miny>50.05576</miny>
    <maxx>10.58601</maxx>
    <maxy>50.05576</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydrodb.uta.edu/nws_wgrfc_hourly_mpe/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>NWS-WGRFC Hourly Multi-sensor Precipitation Estimates</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=187</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>mcenery@uta.edu</Email>
    <phone>(817) 272-0234</phone>
    <organization>NOAA's National Weather Service West Gulf River Forecast Center</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.srh.noaa.gov/wgrfc/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>MPE data  from NWS-WGRFC</citation>
    <aabstract>The precipitation data are quality-controlled, multi-sensor (radar, satellite, and rain gauge) precipitation estimates from National Weather Service (NWS) West Gulf River Forecast Center (WGRFC). The original data are in XMRG format and projected in the Hydrologic Rainfall Analysis Project (HRAP) grid coordinate system, a polar stereographic projection true at 60°N / 105°W. The data represent the 1-hour precipitation estimates for each HRAP grid cell located within the WGRFC boundaries.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>2147483647</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>69827</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>187</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>NWS-WGRFC_Hourly_MPE</NetworkName>
    <minx>-108.7541</minx>
    <miny>24.8692</miny>
    <maxx>-93.1711</maxx>
    <maxy>38.4404</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://data.iutahepscor.org/RedButteCreekWOF/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Red Butte Creek GAMUT, Utah, USA</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=3568</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>amber.jones@usu.edu</Email>
    <phone>(435) 797-7147</phone>
    <organization>University of Utah, iUTAH EPSCoR</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://gamut.iutahepscor.org</orgwebsite>
    <citation>iUTAH GAMUT Working Group. (2014), GAMUT Ecohydrologic Data, 1.0, iUTAH Modeling and Data Federation, http://data.iutahepscor.org</citation>
    <aabstract>iUTAH researchers have developed and deployed an ecohydrologic observatory to study water in ‘Gradients Along Mountain to Urban Transitions’ (GAMUT). The GAMUT Network measures aspects of climate, hydrology, and water quality along a mountain-to-urban gradient in three watersheds that share common water sources (winter-derived precipitation) but differ in the human and biophysical nature of land-use transitions. GAMUT includes state-of-the-art sensors at aquatic and terrestrial sites for real-time monitoring of common meteorological variables, snow accumulation and melt, soil moisture, surface water flow, and surface water quality.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>57165340</valuecount>
    <variablecount>130</variablecount>
    <sitecount>19</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>3568</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>Red Butte Creek GAMUT</NetworkName>
    <minx>-111.9176</minx>
    <miny>40.7416</miny>
    <maxx>-111.7655</maxx>
    <maxy>40.81012</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/unh_snow/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Estimated Snow Water Equivalent Across the U.S.</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5580</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jennifer.jacobs@unh.edu</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>University of New Hampshire Environmental Research Group</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.unh.edu/erg/</orgwebsite>
    <citation />
    <aabstract>The Advanced Microwave Scanning Radiometer - Earth Observing System (AMSR-E) daily passive microwave snow water equivalent (SWE) datasets are made available from the National Snow and Ice Data Center (NSIDC). SWE is calculated using the brightness temperature observations from the AMSR-E instrument aboard NASA's Aqua satellite.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>9252620</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>2758</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5580</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>UNH_Snow</NetworkName>
    <minx>-101.5702</minx>
    <miny>28.2825</miny>
    <maxx>-67.24762</maxx>
    <maxy>48.94306</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://icewater.usu.edu/loganriver/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Logan River Observations, Northern Utah, USA</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=128</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>milada_majerova@yahoo.com</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>Watershed Sciences Department, Utah State University</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.usu.edu</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Majerova, M., and J. Schmidt (2009), Logan River Observations Data, Utah State University, Logan, UT, USA.</citation>
    <aabstract>This dataset contains observations of stage, discharge, and water temperature in the Logan River, which is located in northern Utah, USA.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>877985</valuecount>
    <variablecount>5</variablecount>
    <sitecount>4</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>128</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>LoganRiver</NetworkName>
    <minx>-111.6579</minx>
    <miny>41.77034</miny>
    <maxx>-111.5647</maxx>
    <maxy>41.93315</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydrodata.info/webservices/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Central European Climate Data</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=196</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jirikadlec2@gmail.com</Email>
    <phone>208-313-8076</phone>
    <organization>Charles University Prague</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://hydro.natur.cuni.cz</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Kadlec, J. and Mazanec,L. 2011. Central European Daily Precipitation and Air Temperature Data. Central European Climate Network. Research Group of Hydrology &amp; Climatology, Charles University in Prague, Faculty of Science. Data retrieved fro CUAHSI HIS on July 28, 2011. </citation>
    <aabstract>The quality controlled daily values come from following sources: NOAA synoptic stations, ECA&amp;D European Climate assessment dataset, GHCN historical climate station network and several volunteer observatories. An automated quality control algorithm is run before publishing the values through the service. Data is available for Czechia, Slovakia, Poland, Hungary, Austria and Germany and is updated on a weekly basis.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>7298942</valuecount>
    <variablecount>4</variablecount>
    <sitecount>358</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>196</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>HCLIMATE</NetworkName>
    <minx>6.05</minx>
    <miny>46</miny>
    <maxx>23.617</maxx>
    <maxy>54.917</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydro.library.oregonstate.edu/OHIS/cuahsi_1_0.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Willamette Water 2100</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=2501</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>myrica.mccune@oregonstate.edu</Email>
    <phone>541-737-8143</phone>
    <organization>Oregon State University</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://oregonstate.edu/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Oregon Hydrologic Information System Database. Oregon State University Libraries, Institute for Natural Resources, Institute for Water and Watersheds, and the College of Earth, Oceanic, and Atmospheric Sciences at Oregon State University.</citation>
    <aabstract>This project evaluates how climate change, population growth, and economic growth will change the availability and the use of water in the Willamette River Basin (WRB) on a decadal to centennial timescale. The five-year project began in October 2010, and is a collaborative effort of faculty from Oregon State University (OSU), the University of Oregon (UO), and Portland State University (PSU). It is funded by the National Science Foundation.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>200760</valuecount>
    <variablecount>9</variablecount>
    <sitecount>1</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>2501</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>WW2100 OHIS</NetworkName>
    <minx>-123.2855</minx>
    <miny>44.55843</miny>
    <maxx>-123.2855</maxx>
    <maxy>44.55843</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/czo_boulder/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Boulder Creek Critical Zone Observatory</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=159</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>Suzanne.Anderson@colorado.edu</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>University of Colorado at Boulder</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://czo.colorado.edu</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Logistical support and/or data were provided by the NSF-supported Boulder Creek Critical Zone Observatory</citation>
    <aabstract>The Boulder Creek Critical Zone Observatory (CZO), located in the Front Range of Colorado, is designed to examine the effect of erosion on the development and function of the Critical Zone. The Critical Zone is the near-surface region that supports terrestrial life, extending vertically from the base of groundwater to the upper reaches of the vegetation canopy. The Boulder Creek Watershed is about 1160km2 and drains the Front Range from the Continental Divide (4120m) to the eastern plains (1480) (Murphy, 2000). In the upper reaches of Boulder Creek, it has 3 tributaries – North Boulder Creek, Middle Boulder Creek and South Boulder Creek. The confluence of North Boulder Creek and Middle Boulder Creek is at ?m. South Boulder Creek joins Boulder Creek near the City of Boulder. The large elevation range within the watershed encompasses five climatic zones – alpine, subalpine, montane, foothills and plains. Total annual precipitation generally decreases with elevation, from &gt;100cm at the Continental Divide to about 46cm near the City of Boulder. The project will focus on the upper basin of the Boulder Creek Watershed (above the City of Boulder).</aabstract>
    <valuecount>30450</valuecount>
    <variablecount>33</variablecount>
    <sitecount>2</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>159</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>czo_boulder</NetworkName>
    <minx>-105.6165</minx>
    <miny>40.01247</miny>
    <maxx>-105.4689</maxx>
    <maxy>40.05479</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://icewater.boisestate.edu/srbdataservices/cuahsi_1_0.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Snake River Basin, Modeled Streamflow</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=199</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>vsridhar@boisestate.edu</Email>
    <phone>208-426-3710</phone>
    <organization>Boise State University, Civil Engineering</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://coen.boisestate.edu/ce/home.asp</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Dr.Venkataramana Sridhar, 2011, VIC Modeled Streamflow, Idaho, Boise State University.</citation>
    <aabstract>Preliminary Streamflow simulated by the Variable Infiltration Capacity (VIC) model.  A file is created for each climate model and emission scenario. Daily values of streamflow in this dataset is the routed flow for a specific location using the routing algorithm after the surface runoff is calculated by the hydrology model. The daily dischage is the daily average in cubic feet per second (cfs) at the mid day (1200 hour).  Terrestrial Hydroclimate Simulation Lab (Civil Engineering), Boise State University,Boise, Idaho. </aabstract>
    <valuecount>32872</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>1</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>199</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>SRB</NetworkName>
    <minx>-111.905</minx>
    <miny>43.8258</miny>
    <maxx>-111.905</maxx>
    <maxy>43.8258</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydrodata.info/chmi-d/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?wsdl</servURL>
    <Title>Hydrodata.cz daily data</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=320</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jirikadlec2@gmail.com</Email>
    <phone>208-313-8076</phone>
    <organization>Hydrodata.cz Czech data centre</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://hydrodata.cz</orgwebsite>
    <citation>data from hydrodata.cz website collected by CHMI, Povodi Vltavy, Povodi Labe and Povodi Ohre</citation>
    <aabstract>The target of the open source hydrodata.cz web application and web services is to bridge the gap between modelers and field hydrologists by providing free, publicly accessible precipitation, snow, temperature, and discharge data series from multiple organizations in the Czech Republic using the standardized the CUAHSI WaterML data format and search services. Data providers contributing to this effort include the CUAHSI, NOAA, Charles University experimental watershed network, Czech watershed authorities, and networks of volunteer observers. Time period covered includes the floods of 2006, 2009, 2010 and 2011 as well as the 2007 drought. Adopting the WaterML standard also allows the use of other free third party client side web based and desktop data discovery software tools – which has the added benefit of making the Czech Republic hydrological data more readily accessible to the international community.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>120486796</valuecount>
    <variablecount>7</variablecount>
    <sitecount>1198</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>320</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>HYDRODATACZ-D</NetworkName>
    <minx>12.1797</minx>
    <miny>48.59366</miny>
    <maxx>18.89149</maxx>
    <maxy>51.0008</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/GLEON_Sunapee/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Lake Sunapee, NH, USA, Instrumented Buoy</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=3553</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>junef@lakesunapee.org</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>Lake Sunapee Protective Association </organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.lakesunapee.org/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Weathers, K.C.,  J. Fichter, J. Merriman, C. Carey, D. Richardson, D. Bruseciwicz (2014). Lake Sunapee GLEON buoy data. 
</citation>
    <aabstract>The Lake Sunapee GLEON Buoy was envisioned by Kathleen Weathers and the Lake Sunapee Protective Association (LSPA) in 2005 after Weathers visited Trout Lake Station and heard Tim Kratz talk about the nascent GLEON.  The buoy was  funded, built, and is maintained by the Lake Sunapee Protective Association, with  partial financial support from the Frey Foundation, and  in consultation and collaboration with Weathers and GLEON scientists.   Buoy data collection began in August 2007 and was continuous until the winter of 2008, when it sustained ice damage.  After 2008, the buoy is deployed to its Loon Island Lighthouse location for the summer months from approximately May-October.  Real time data are displayed that the LSPA website (www.lakesunapee.org) and archived for use within the GLEON network and beyond.  Lake Sunapee buoy data have been used in many GLEON publications (www.gleon.org).</aabstract>
    <valuecount>663810</valuecount>
    <variablecount>15</variablecount>
    <sitecount>1</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>3553</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>GLEON_Sunapee</NetworkName>
    <minx>-72.05767</minx>
    <miny>43.39133</miny>
    <maxx>-72.05767</maxx>
    <maxy>43.39133</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://data.iutahepscor.org/LoganRiverWOF/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Logan River GAMUT, Utah, USA</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=3566</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>amber.jones@usu.edu</Email>
    <phone>(435) 797-7147</phone>
    <organization>Utah State University, iUTAH EPSCoR</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://gamut.iutahepscor.org</orgwebsite>
    <citation>iUTAH GAMUT Working Group. (2014), GAMUT Ecohydrologic Data, 1.0, iUTAH Modeling and Data Federation, http://data.iutahepscor.org</citation>
    <aabstract>iUTAH researchers have developed and deployed an ecohydrologic observatory to study water in ‘Gradients Along Mountain to Urban Transitions’ (GAMUT). The GAMUT Network measures aspects of climate, hydrology, and water quality along a mountain-to-urban gradient in three watersheds that share common water sources (winter-derived precipitation) but differ in the human and biophysical nature of land-use transitions. GAMUT includes state-of-the-art sensors at aquatic and terrestrial sites for real-time monitoring of common meteorological variables, snow accumulation and melt, soil moisture, surface water flow, and surface water quality.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>48307677</valuecount>
    <variablecount>121</variablecount>
    <sitecount>13</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>3566</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>Logan River GAMUT</NetworkName>
    <minx>-111.8869</minx>
    <miny>41.70443</miny>
    <maxx>-111.5075</maxx>
    <maxy>41.9502</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://icewater.usu.edu/mudlake/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Mud Lake, Idaho, USA</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=12</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jeff.horsburgh@usu.edu</Email>
    <phone>435-797-2946</phone>
    <organization>Utah Water Research Laboratory, Utah State University</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://uwrl.usu.edu</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Horsburgh, J. S., D. K. Stevens, N. O. Mesner, and C. Allen (2009), Data collected in Mud Lake at the Bear Lake National Wildlife Refuge, Idaho, USA, Utah State University.</citation>
    <aabstract>Monitoring at the Bear Lake National Wildlife Refuge has been aimed at creating the monitoring infrastructure needed to more accurately assess sediment and nutrient loads entering and leaving Mud Lake, and providing managers with the data and information needed to better understand how Mud Lake affects the sediment and nutrient loads within the system. Continuous water quality monitoring equipment has been installed at 4 sites around the periphery of Mud Lake to monitor the water quality of its major inflows and outflows. These sites include: 1) the Rainbow Inlet Canal where it flows into Mud Lake; 2) the causeway at the north end of Bear Lake where Bear River Water enters Bear Lake from Mud Lake; 3) the Lifton pumping station where water is pumped out of Bear Lake; and 4) the Outlet Canal where water from Bear Lake and Mud Lake leaves the complex and flows North and back into the Bear River. Continuous flow measurements at these locations have been provided by PacifiCorp Energy using existing equipment at those sites.  Utah State University has worked together with the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service and the State of Idaho Department of Environmental Quality to collect these data.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>1601388</valuecount>
    <variablecount>34</variablecount>
    <sitecount>12</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>12</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>MudLake</NetworkName>
    <minx>-111.3417</minx>
    <miny>42.12035</miny>
    <maxx>-111.2884</maxx>
    <maxy>42.25035</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/nwisuv/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>NWIS Unit Values</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=3</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>help@cuahsi.org</Email>
    <phone>339-221-5400</phone>
    <organization>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS)</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://waterdata.usgs.gov/nwis</orgwebsite>
    <citation>USGS National Water Information System.</citation>
    <aabstract>The USGS National Water Information System (NWIS) provides access to millions of sites measuring streamflow, groundwater levels, and water quality. This web service provides methods for retrieving Real Time data from NWIS. For more information about NWIS, see the NWIS home page at http://waterdata.usgs.gov/nwis</aabstract>
    <valuecount>69741006</valuecount>
    <variablecount>175</variablecount>
    <sitecount>15365</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>3</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>NWISUV</NetworkName>
    <minx>-999</minx>
    <miny>-999</miny>
    <maxx>144.9257</maxx>
    <maxy>70.49538</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://data.iutahepscor.org/littlebearriverwof/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Little Bear River Experimental Watershed, Northern Utah, USA</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=52</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jeff.horsburgh@usu.edu</Email>
    <phone>435-797-2946</phone>
    <organization>Utah Water Research Laboratory, Utah State University</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://littlebearriver.usu.edu</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Horsburgh, J. S., D. K. Stevens, D. G. Tarboton, N. O. Mesner, A. Spackman Jones, and S. Gurrero (2009) Monitoring data collected within the Little Bear River Experimental Watershed, Utah, USA, Utah State University.</citation>
    <aabstract>Utah State University is conducting continuous monitoring within the Little Bear River watershed of northern Utah, USA to investiage the use of surrogate measures such as turbidity in creating high frequency load estimates for constituents that cannot be measured continuously.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>33362716</valuecount>
    <variablecount>61</variablecount>
    <sitecount>16</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>52</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>LittleBearRiver</NetworkName>
    <minx>-111.9464</minx>
    <miny>41.49541</miny>
    <maxx>-111.7993</maxx>
    <maxy>41.71847</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://icewater.boisestate.edu/dcew2dataservices/cuahsi_1_0.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Dry Creek Experimental Watershed, SW Idaho</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=122</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>pamaishlin@boisestate.edu</Email>
    <phone>208-426-2220</phone>
    <organization>Boise State University, Hydrologic Sciences Department</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://earth.boisestate.edu/jmcnamara/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Hydrologic Sciences, Dept of Geosciences, Boise State University, Dr. Jim McNamara</citation>
    <aabstract>Dry Creek Experimental Watershed was established by Dr. Jim McNamara in 1998 as an outdoor laboratory for student and faculty research toward improving understanding of hydrologic processes in semi-arid mountainous terrain to facilitate testing and improving data integration and hydrologic modeling. Continuous and discrete data collection includes climate, surface water, groundwater and soil parameters, both chemical and physical, over a range of spatial and temporal scales. </aabstract>
    <valuecount>4277320</valuecount>
    <variablecount>11</variablecount>
    <sitecount>7</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>122</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>ODMDCEW2</NetworkName>
    <minx>-116.1786</minx>
    <miny>43.68834</miny>
    <maxx>-116.0904</maxx>
    <maxy>43.75877</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://www.his.npca.ca/waterdataservices_quantity/cuahsi_1_0.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Niagara Peninsula Conservation Authority Water Quantity Data Service</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=129</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>gverkade@npca.ca</Email>
    <phone>(905)788-3135</phone>
    <organization>Niagara Peninsula Conservation Authority</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.his.npca.ca/hydroserver</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Niagara Peninsula Conservation Authority, 2011. Water Quantity monitoring data collected within the Niagara Peninsula Conservation Authority Watershed, Ontario.</citation>
    <aabstract>This database contains historic and near real time water quantity observation data for the Niagara Peninsula Conservation Authority watershed. Variables collected include water level, stream flow, precipitation and air temperature and water temperature.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>7279681</valuecount>
    <variablecount>11</variablecount>
    <sitecount>26</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>129</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>NPCA</NetworkName>
    <minx>-79.82583</minx>
    <miny>-79.24709</miny>
    <maxx>42.99408</maxx>
    <maxy>43.23337</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://icewater.geology.isu.edu/PortneufWatershed/cuahsi_1_0.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Portneuf Watershed Observations, Idaho</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=140</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>whittifa@isu.edu</Email>
    <phone>208-360-7793</phone>
    <organization>Idaho State University</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://gsl.geology.isu.edu/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Sigler, J.W. 2011. Monitoring data collected within the Portneuf River, Idaho. Portneuf Watershed Partnership. </citation>
    <aabstract>Stakeholders within the Portneuf Basin have joined together to form a coalition known as the Portneuf Watershed Partnership (PWP). This group has both a monitoring and outreach/education component and is a cooperative effort of private industry; educational institutions; scientists and government agencies at numerous levels (City; County; State; Tribal and Federal). Support and cooperation for the PWP has been provided by many agencies. In addition to funds and contributions of labor or materials many volunteers and property owners have contributed labor or cooperated by providing access to their lands.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>1805839</valuecount>
    <variablecount>6</variablecount>
    <sitecount>4</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>140</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>PWP</NetworkName>
    <minx>-112.545</minx>
    <miny>42.62439</miny>
    <maxx>-112.1171</maxx>
    <maxy>42.93505</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/czo_arizona/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Catalina-Jemez CZO - Jemez River Basin</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=158</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>chorover@cals.arizona.edu</Email>
    <phone>520-626-5635</phone>
    <organization>University of Arizona</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://criticalzone.org/catalina-jemez/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Logistical support and/or data were provided by the NSF-supported Jemez River Basin and Santa Catalina Mountains Critical Zone Observatory under the NSF EAR-0724958</citation>
    <aabstract>This data service provides data collected from Jemez River Basin sites. 
We are developing an interdisciplinary observatory in the southwestern US that will improve our fundamental understanding of the function, structure and co-evolution of biota, soils, and landforms that comprise the Critical Zone (CZ). The observatory is designed as a natural laboratory for the earth science community to test hypotheses related to CZ function in relation to climatic and water cycle variation. We posit that CZ systems organize and evolve in response to open system fluxes of energy and mass that can be quantified at point to watershed scales. These fluxes include meteoric CZ inputs of radiation, water, and carbon that are modulated by surficial biota to produce fluids and biogeochemical components that undergo biotic and abiotic transformation during gradient-driven transport. We hypothesize that the coupling of physical, chemical and biological processes is related specifically and predictably to the timing and magnitude of these fluxes. Therefore, our CZ Observatory (CZO) is designed to examine the impacts of space-time variability in energy and water flux on coupled CZ processes along two well-constrained climate gradients. The first is on rhyolitic parent material in the Jemez River Basin of northern New Mexico (JRB) and the second is on granite and schist bedrock within the Santa Catalina Mountains in southern Arizona (SCM). Measurement, modeling, and experimentation at sites that vary in parent rock, elevation, aspect, slope, soil development, and vegetation will enable quantification of the feedbacks between energy and mass fluxes (driven by chemical and physical gradients) and measured components of CZ structure. Our team has developed an iterative modeling and measurement strategy, and a management structure that fosters integration among disciplines. The JRB-SCM CZO is organized around broad questions that require an integrated, multi-disciplinary approach including the following two: How does variability in energy input and related mass flux influence CZ structure and function? How do feedbacks between landscape evolution and the cycling of water and carbon alter short- and long-term CZ development? To identify the couplings among physical, chemical, and biological processes, our research integrates four crosscutting science themes that are both multi-disciplinary and multi-scale: Ecohydrology and Hydrologic Partitioning, Subsurface Biogeochemistry, Landscape Evolution and Surface Water Dynamics. We are employing an integrated process-based modeling approach to (i) identify optimal sites for measuring structure and process, (ii) refine hypotheses developed through field-based observation and measurements, (iii) explore feedbacks and emergent system behaviors, and (iv) develop transfer functions that can be used to relate system behavior across scales and modes of observation. Discoveries made at the JRB-SCM CZO will improve our ability to predict CZ response to changes in climate and land cover, which is immediately useful to regional resource managers and will ultimately inform broader-scale decision making. We coordinate closely with other CZOs to support data collection, storage, and dissemination. Our education and outreach activities are built upon other highly effective educational efforts developed and led at UA. We are developing a range of products and activities for K-16 students, the general public, and stakeholders, including summer Observatory field experiences for local high school and undergraduate students, graduate courses, and field camps in earth science, as well as coordination of related efforts by other science centers active in the region. We invite new investigators throughout the global earth sciences community to conduct novel and collaborative research at the JRB-SCM CZO</aabstract>
    <valuecount>6324710</valuecount>
    <variablecount>36</variablecount>
    <sitecount>13</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>158</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>czo_ariz</NetworkName>
    <minx>-106.5978</minx>
    <miny>35.84785</miny>
    <maxx>-106.4497</maxx>
    <maxy>35.9092</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/czo_luquillo/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Luquillo Critical Zone Observatory</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=160</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>leonmi@sas.upenn.edu</Email>
    <phone>215-746-5974</phone>
    <organization>University of Pennsylvania</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.sas.upenn.edu/lczo/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Luquillo CZO, NSF Award # 1331841</citation>
    <aabstract>The Luquillo Critical Zone Observatory (LCZO) is located in Luquillo Mountains of northeastern Puerto Rico. The multi-disciplinary team of geoscientists working at the site are addressing a set of specific hypotheses that are related to the following overarching questions: How do critical zone processes and the flow and transformations of material differ in landscapes with contrasting bedrock but similar climates, land use, and geologic histories? What are the implications of these differences for the long term sustainability of water and soil resources? Research Overview Specifically, the observatory is quantifying and comparing critical zone (CZ) processes in landforms and watersheds underlain by three different rock types, granodiorites, volcaniclastics, and their associated contact metamorphic rocks. Previous research has demonstrated that these are some of the most rapidly eroding watersheds in the world. There are also dramatic, but poorly quantified, contrasts in CZ processes between areas underlain by these bedrocks. Individual research project include studies of deep weathering, soil formation and soil carbon accumulation, riparian zone dynamics, fluvial geomorphology, and meteorology. Infrastructure includes weather stations, instrumented soil pits and riparian zones, and stream flow gages. The principal researchers and students involve in the Luquillo Critical Zone Observatory are from the UPENN, the Pennsylvania State University, the University of California at Berkeley, the University of New Hampshire, the University of Puerto Rico, the US Geological Survey, and the US Forest Service International Institute of Tropical Forestry. The Observatory will also provide facilities for collaborators from a host of US and International Universities and Research Centers.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>5840121</valuecount>
    <variablecount>76</variablecount>
    <sitecount>9</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>160</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>czo_luquillo</NetworkName>
    <minx>-65.76384</minx>
    <miny>18.27971</miny>
    <maxx>-65.73111</maxx>
    <maxy>18.33111</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/czo_merced/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Southern Sierra Critical Zone Observatory</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=161</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>rbales@ucmerced.edu</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>University of California, Merced</organization>
    <orgwebsite>https://snri.ucmerced.edu/CZO</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Logistical support and/or data were provided by the NSF-supported Southern Sierra Critical Zone Observatory</citation>
    <aabstract>The Southern Sierra CZO is a community platform for research on critical-zone processes across the rain-snow transition in the mixed-conifer forest of the Southern Sierra Nevada. While this elevation range has characteristically rapid seasonal changes, going from snow cover to wet soil to dry soil over a 1-2 month period, climate warming will shift this transition period earlier or eliminate it entirely at the current transitional elevation. The characteristic spatial differences along gradients offer the opportunity to substitute space for time, making the CZO an excellent natural laboratory for studying how critical zone processes respond to perturbations, and particularly how the water cycle drives critical zone processes. A team of scientists from multiple institutions is carrying out research at the CZO, which is located in the Kings River Experimental Watershed (KREW), a U.S. Forest Service watershed-level, integrated ecosystem project for long-term research in headwater catchments in the Sierra National Forest.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>26613545</valuecount>
    <variablecount>17</variablecount>
    <sitecount>65</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>161</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>czo_merced</NetworkName>
    <minx>-119.2044</minx>
    <miny>36.95894</miny>
    <maxx>-119.0266</maxx>
    <maxy>37.07042</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/czo_psu/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Susquehanna Shale Hills CZO</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=162</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jzw126@psu.edu</Email>
    <phone>814-865-9910</phone>
    <organization>Pennsylvania State University</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.czo.psu.edu</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Logistical support and/or data were provided by the NSF-supported Shale Hills Susquehanna Critical Zone Observatory.</citation>
    <aabstract>The Shale Hills Critical Zone Observatory (CZO) is a forested, small, temperate-climate catchment in central Pennsylvania in which the regolith is developing upon homogeneous shale. The purpose of the observatory and associated interdisciplinary research is to quantitatively predict the creation, evolution, and structure of regolith as a function of the geochemical, hydrologic, biologic, and geomorphologic processes operating in a temperate, forested landscape. By creating an interdisciplinary team working collaboratively in one observatory we aim to advance methods for characterizing regolith, to provide a theoretical basis for predicting the distribution and properties of regolith, and to theoretically and experimentally study the impacts of regolith on fluid pathways, flow rates, and residence times. The research site, the focus of National Science Foundation-supported research since the 1970s, has comprehensive datasets on distributed water budgets (1970-75), has served as a model test bed for hydrological response (1998-present), and will be augmented here by new geochemical, geomorphological, ecological, lidar, and soils datasets, all available to the research community. Shale Hills CZO represents an opportunity to investigate the rates and mechanisms of saprolite and soil formation on a relatively simple but ubiquitous bedrock lithology that has been documented to be important in determining global fluxes of C, P, and platinum–group elements worldwide. Furthermore, the regolith at Shale Hills has experienced at least two potentially significant perturbations in the geologically recent past: a climatic perturbation from periglacial to modern conditions, and a biologic perturbation from anthropogenic clearing of forests during and repeatedly since colonial occupation. The magnitude of these perturbations and their influence on regolith generation afford an opportunity to assess the time scales of response of soil production to both long-term climate change and human activity.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>71158095</valuecount>
    <variablecount>49</variablecount>
    <sitecount>39</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>162</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>czo_psu</NetworkName>
    <minx>-77.90734</minx>
    <miny>40.66375</miny>
    <maxx>-77.90315</maxx>
    <maxy>40.66583</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://www.his.npca.ca/waterdataservices_quality/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Niagara Peninsula Conservation Authority Water Quality Data Service</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=171</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>gverkade@npca.ca</Email>
    <phone>905-788-3135</phone>
    <organization>Niagara Peninsula Conservation Authority</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.his.npca.ca/hydroserver</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Niagara Peninsula Conservation Authority, 2011. Water Quality monitoring data collected within the Niagara Peninsula Conservation Authority Watershed, Ontario.</citation>
    <aabstract>This database contains historic water quality observation data for the Niagara Peninsula Conservation Authority watershed.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>148720</valuecount>
    <variablecount>67</variablecount>
    <sitecount>71</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>171</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>NPCAQUAL</NetworkName>
    <minx>-79.95966</minx>
    <miny>42.84816</miny>
    <maxx>-78.93753</maxx>
    <maxy>43.25733</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/muddyriver/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Muddy River Water Quality Monitoring Project</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=181</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>fhellweger@gmail.com</Email>
    <phone>(617) 373-3992</phone>
    <organization>Northeastern University</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.muddyrivermmoc.org/index.html</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Hellweger, F. L., Wei, I., Mathew, M., Jain, K., 2007. Muddy River water quality monitoring sampling and analysis plan. MuddyRiver. Civil &amp; Environmental Engineering Department, Northeastern University, Boston. Data retrieved from CUAHSI HIS on March 18, 2011. </citation>
    <aabstract>The Muddy River is located in Brookline and Boston, Massachusetts and is tributary to the lower Charles River. The watershed has drainage area of 6.32 mi2, an average slope of 7.2 percent and mixed land use (46% single family, 14% multi-family, 10%
commercial, 16% urban open, 7% forest, 7% other, USGS). The river has been altered
significantly from its natural form. It is part of the Emerald Necklace park system
designed by Frederick Law Olmsted in the late 1800’s. The Muddy River is designated
by the MA DEP as Class B (fishable, swimmable)The Muddy River, like many other urban rivers, has been subject to significant pollution,
including combined sewer discharges, urban runoff discharges, shoreline encroachment,
culverting, etc. Several recent floods have caused significant property damage and recent studies have identified water quality concerns, which lead to the Muddy River Restoration Project.
Northeastern University carried out a 3-year water quality monitoring project. Samples were collected three times per quarter, from 14 stations and analyzed for 36 parameters. Details of the procedures were presented previously in the Sampling and Analysis Plan (SAP) (dated April 13, 2007). The historical data were summarized in a Historical Data Report (dated March 7, 2007). Data, including data quality results and discussion were
submitted on a quarterly basis in 13 Data Reports. The purpose of this final report is to summarize and discuss the data, and to provide recommendations for future studies.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>9290</valuecount>
    <variablecount>31</variablecount>
    <sitecount>14</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>181</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>MuddyRiver</NetworkName>
    <minx>-71.1179</minx>
    <miny>42.32238</miny>
    <maxx>-71.09175</maxx>
    <maxy>42.34918</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydrodb.uta.edu/nws_wgrfc_daily_mpe_recent_values/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>NWS-WGRFC Daily Multi-sensor Precipitation Estimates Recent Values</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=189</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>mcenery@uta.edu</Email>
    <phone>(817) 272-0234</phone>
    <organization>NOAA's National Weather Service West Gulf River Forecast Center</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.srh.noaa.gov/wgrfc/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>MPE data from NWS-WGRFC</citation>
    <aabstract>The precipitation data are quality-controlled, multi-sensor (radar, satellite, and rain gauge) precipitation estimates from National Weather Service (NWS) West Gulf River Forecast Center. The original data are in XMRG format and projected in the Hydrologic Rainfall Analysis Project (HRAP) grid coordinate system, a polar stereographic projection true at 60°N / 105°W. The data represent the 24-hour precipitation estimates for each HRAP grid cell.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>32513436</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>69821</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>189</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>NWS_WGRFC_Daily_MPE_Recent_Values</NetworkName>
    <minx>-108.7541</minx>
    <miny>24.8692</miny>
    <maxx>-93.1711</maxx>
    <maxy>38.4404</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/rmbl/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Rocky Mountain Biological Laboratory Environmental Monitoring</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5589</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>Help@cuahsi.org</Email>
    <phone>339-221-5400</phone>
    <organization>Rocky Mountain Biological Laboratory</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.rmbl.org/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Rocky Mountain Biological Laboratory Environmental Monitoring data. Accessed via the CUAHSI Water Data Center. Original data available: http://www.wrcc.dri.edu/rmbl/</citation>
    <aabstract>This data set has been created by the Rocky Mountain Biological Laboratory's (RMBL) Environmental Monitoring. As part of a working group in the Global Network of Mountain Observatories (GNOMO), CUAHSI staff downloaded RMBL's data from the Western Regional Climate Center, formatted metadata, and re-published the data using CUAHSI's Cloud HydroServer.  </aabstract>
    <valuecount>289669</valuecount>
    <variablecount>27</variablecount>
    <sitecount>6</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5589</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>RMBL</NetworkName>
    <minx>-107.0636</minx>
    <miny>38.65472</miny>
    <maxx>-106.8617</maxx>
    <maxy>39.02833</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://icewater.boisestate.edu/rcew2dataservices/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL </servURL>
    <Title>Reynolds Creek Experimental Watershed, SW Idaho</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=173</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>mark.seyfried@ars.usda.gov</Email>
    <phone>208-422-0715</phone>
    <organization>Northwest Watershed Research Center, Agricultural Research Service, U.S. Dept of Agriculture</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.ars.usda.gov/Main/site_main.htm?modecode=53-62-00-00</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Seyfried, M. S., M. D. Murdock, C. L. Hanson, G. N. Flerchinger, and S. Van Vactor, Long-term soil water content database, Reynolds Creek Experimental Watershed, Idaho, USA, Water Resources Research, 37, 2847-2851, 2001.
</citation>
    <aabstract>The Reynolds Creek Experimental Watershed, Southwest Idaho, USA, funded by the Unites States Department of Agriculture has continuously monitored a large variety of hydrologic parameters since the early 1960's.
</aabstract>
    <valuecount>13058645</valuecount>
    <variablecount>4</variablecount>
    <sitecount>70</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>173</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>ODMRCEW2</NetworkName>
    <minx>-116.8562</minx>
    <miny>43.06573</miny>
    <maxx>-116.7025</maxx>
    <maxy>43.29692</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydro10.sdsc.edu/vtrain/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?wsdl</servURL>
    <Title>Vietnam Precipitation 1975-2006</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=299</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>qdo@worldbank.org</Email>
    <phone>202-473-1248</phone>
    <organization>Vietnam's HydroMeteorological Data Center </organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://go.worldbank.org/TSULIZ6JE0</orgwebsite>
    <citation>"Natural Disasters and Household Welfare: Evidence from Vietnam", T. Thomas, L. Christiaensen, Q. Do, and L. Trung, World Bank Policy Research Working Paper No. 5491, December 2010.</citation>
    <aabstract>The rainfall data are obtained from Vietnam's HydroMeteorological Data Center (http://www.hymetdata.gov.vn/), and cover daily observations from 172 weather stations. Most of them were actively operated through out the period 1975-2006. The list of weather stations with GIS coordinates is also provided.

The data are provided in MS Excel files. Each file contains data from one weather station.

Please note:
1.Blank cells in years for which the weather stations were active mean absolute no rainfall.
2.Cells with 0.0 (mm of rainfall) mean that there was some rainfall but it was too little to measure.
3.In years the weather stations were not active or for some reasons the data were not collected, the cells are marked by an X or a note showing that data in those years were not collected.

We are revising the data so that errors will be eliminated and the data are better organized. Version 2 is expected to come out by April 15th, 2011.

For any inqueries in regards to the use of data, please contact us at: Quy-Toan Do (The World Bank, qdo@worldbank.org) or Le Dang Trung (Univesity of Copenhagen, trung@foi.dk)</aabstract>
    <valuecount>1126730</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>172</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>299</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>vtrain</NetworkName>
    <minx>102.5</minx>
    <miny>8.01</miny>
    <maxx>114.2</maxx>
    <maxy>22.57</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/YosemiteHydroclimateNetwork/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Yosemite Hydroclimate Network</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5587</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jdlund@u.washington.edu</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>University of Washington</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://depts.washington.edu/mtnhydr/data/yosemite.shtml</orgwebsite>
    <citation> J. D. Lundquist (2015) Yosemite Hydroclimate Network.</citation>
    <aabstract>The Yosemite Hydroclimate Network, part of University of Washington, strive to help students and the general public understand how large-scale weather and climate patterns affect the supply of water they drink.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>3779259</valuecount>
    <variablecount>6</variablecount>
    <sitecount>68</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5587</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>YosemiteHydroclimateNetwork</NetworkName>
    <minx>-119.917</minx>
    <miny>37.5</miny>
    <maxx>-118.967</maxx>
    <maxy>38.25</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/Mazar_River_Project/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Mazar River Project</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5592</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>director@cordilleratropical.org</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>Fundacion Cordillera Tropical (FCT) and University of Vermont (UVM)</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.cordilleratropical.org/en/Programs/MazarRiver/hydrological.html</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Fundacion Cordillera Tropical and University of Vermont. (Date) Mazar River Project.  Cuenca, Ecuador and Burlington, Vermont</citation>
    <aabstract>The Mazar River Project established a hydrological monitoring station in southern Ecuador on the Mazar River, a tributary of the Paute River Basin, situated on the eastern Andean cordillera. The station is equipped with sensors to continuously monitor stream stage and turbidity and an automated sampler for event-based collection of stream water samples, providing high frequency data that reduces the uncertainty of observations. During its first year of observation, the program is generating continuous observations of runoff and turbidity. The data will be used to establish relationships between turbidity and concentrations of total suspended solids (TSS) and total particulate phosphorus (TP), and provide estimates of annual loads of TSS and TP. </aabstract>
    <valuecount>56499</valuecount>
    <variablecount>3</variablecount>
    <sitecount>2</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5592</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>Mazar_River_Project</NetworkName>
    <minx>-78.69891</minx>
    <miny>-2.547323</miny>
    <maxx>-78.67116</maxx>
    <maxy>-2.541523</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://nmhis.unm.edu/RGETWells/cuahsi_1_0.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Rio-ET Wells: Groundwater wells in the Middle Rio Grande</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=191</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jcoonrod@unm.edu</Email>
    <phone>505-277-3233</phone>
    <organization>University of New Mexico</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://bosque.unm.edu/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>J. Cleverly, C. Dahm, J. Coonrod, K. Vanderbilt, 1999-2008, Evapotranspiration tower and well data, Rio-ET: Evapotranspiration Studies in the Middle Rio Grande, University of New Mexico</citation>
    <aabstract>Restoration efforts that remove non-native understory vegetation or dense monotypic stands of non-native vegetation from riparian zones (the bosque) are designed to reduce consumption of water. Quantification of the response of evapotranspiration (ET) and water table depths to non-native understory removal or to eradication of dense stands of non-native species like salt cedar or Russian olive is needed to provide defensible estimates of potential water-savings from restoration activities. In addition to restoration assessment, it is also important to monitor the effects the increasing roles of fire and post-burn management have on ET and water tables. We monitored the ET and water table responses of a site with understory removed (Albuquerque South Valley).</aabstract>
    <valuecount>4307413</valuecount>
    <variablecount>3</variablecount>
    <sitecount>33</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>191</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>RioGrandeETWells</NetworkName>
    <minx>-106.9036</minx>
    <miny>33.7808</miny>
    <maxx>-106.6824</maxx>
    <maxy>35.12675</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/UMass_ARM/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>WRRC Acid Rain Monitoring Project</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=198</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>esfinn@tei.umass.edu</Email>
    <phone>413-545-5979</phone>
    <organization>Massachusetts Water Resources Research Center</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.umass.edu/tei/wrrc/arm/index.html</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Hatte, M. and Finn, E. 2011. Acid Rain Monitoring data. State of Massachusetts. Acid Rain Monitoring Project, Water Resources Research Center, University of Massachusetts, Amherst.</citation>
    <aabstract>The Acid Rain Monitoring Project began at the University of Massachusetts Water Resources Research Center in 1983. The project's mission was initially to develop a comprehensive picture of the sensitivity of Massachusetts surface waters to acid deposition, and later evolved to determine long-term trends in this sensitivity. </aabstract>
    <valuecount>14856</valuecount>
    <variablecount>15</variablecount>
    <sitecount>320</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>198</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>UMass_ARM</NetworkName>
    <minx>-73.4244</minx>
    <miny>41.5469</miny>
    <maxx>-69.9833</maxx>
    <maxy>42.8667</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/LaSelvastreamdischarge/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL </servURL>
    <Title>La Selva Hydrologic Data</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=217</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>genereux@ncsu.edu</Email>
    <phone>(919) 515-6017</phone>
    <organization>North Carolina State University, Department of Marine, Earth and Atmospheric Sciences</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.ots.ac.cr/meteoro/default.php?pestacion=2</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Genereux, D.P., and C. Zanon.  2011.  Stage and Discharge Data for Two Small Streams in a Costa Rican Rain Forest, La Selva Biological Station, 2006-2010.  Published on-line at http://www.ots.ac.cr/meteoro/default.php?pestacion=2, 14 September 2011.</citation>
    <aabstract>During the first half of 1998 two sharp-crested V-notch weirs were constructed at La Selva Biological Station in Costa Rica (a research station owned and operated by the Organization for Tropical Studies, OTS) to measure volumetric stream discharge (streamflow).  A 90-degree weir was built on the Taconazo stream, several meters upstream of where the SUR trail (Sendero Sura) crosses the stream.  A 120 degree weir was built on the Arboleda stream, several meters upstream of the confluence of this stream with the Sura stream.  This data set reports 15-minute stage and discharge values for each weir, for the five calendar years 2006-2010.  Complete meta data can be found on the OTS web site at: http://www.ots.ac.cr/meteoro/default.php?pestacion=2</aabstract>
    <valuecount>678962</valuecount>
    <variablecount>5</variablecount>
    <sitecount>2</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>217</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>LaSelvastreamdischarge</NetworkName>
    <minx>-84.013</minx>
    <miny>10.42917</miny>
    <maxx>-84.001</maxx>
    <maxy>10.43214</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/TuolumneMdw/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Mountain Meadow Restoration with a Changing Climate</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=219</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jdlund@u.washington.edu</Email>
    <phone>206-685-7594</phone>
    <organization>University of Washington - Seattle</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://faculty.washington.edu/jdlund/research/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Lundquist, J.L., S.P. Loheide, F. C. Lott, C.S. Lowry, and C.E. Moore (2011) Monitoring Data collected in Tuolumne Meadows, Yosemite National Park, CA, USA, University of Washington – Seattle.  </citation>
    <aabstract>The Mountain Meadow Restoration with a Changing Climate project was initiated in 2007, continuing until 2011. The project was funded by the National Science Foundation under grant no. 0729830. Data was collected on the Tuolumne River and its tributaries, as well as shallow groundwater levels within Tuolumne Meadows in Yosemite National Park. Data was collected manually, as well as with long term loggers at select locations, by the Univ. of WA and WI in collaboration with the National Park Service. The monitoring network consists of water temperature and discharge, and groundwater levels. Most sites are considered low-impact wilderness installations and as of 2011, select sites have been discontinued.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>536</valuecount>
    <variablecount>5</variablecount>
    <sitecount>7</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>219</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>TuolumneMdw</NetworkName>
    <minx>-119.3814</minx>
    <miny>37.86948</miny>
    <maxx>-119.3311</maxx>
    <maxy>37.88333</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/weiherbach/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Weiherbach catchment long-Term monitoring data</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=221</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email />
    <phone />
    <organization>Karlsruher Institut fur Technologie</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://mds.sommer.at/Web-Service-Admintool/index.php</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Klaus, J. and Zehe, E.: A novel explicit approach to model bromide and pesticide transport in connected soil structures, Hydrol. Earth Syst. Sci., 15, 2127-2144, doi:10.5194/hess-15-2127-2011, 2011. </citation>
    <aabstract>The Weiherbach catchment is an extensively studied hydrological catchment. Starting from the 1990's there have been ongoing hydrological measurement campaigns in the Weiherbach area, which is an intensively used agricultural area. Many PhD theses have been written on the hydrological behaviour of the catchment. Future research projects are already planned which will allow for continuation of the monitoring. This project was funded by Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG), project numbers SCHR 1000/3-1 and ZE 533/5-1.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>1160910</valuecount>
    <variablecount>10</variablecount>
    <sitecount>1</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>221</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>Weiherbach</NetworkName>
    <minx>8.739691</minx>
    <miny>49.1411</miny>
    <maxx>8.739691</maxx>
    <maxy>49.1411</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydrodb.uta.edu/LMRFC_Data/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>NWS-LMRFC Hourly Multi Sensor Precipitation Estimates</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=226</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>mcenery@uta.edu</Email>
    <phone>(817)272-0234</phone>
    <organization>NOAA's National Weather Service Lower Mississippi River Forecast Center</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.srh.noaa.gov/lmrfc/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>MPE data from NWS-LMRFC </citation>
    <aabstract>The precipitation data are quality-controlled, multi-sensor (radar, satellite, and rain gauge) precipitation estimates from National Weather Service (NWS) Lower Missisippi River Forecast Center. The original data are in XMRG format and projected in the Hydrologic Rainfall Analysis Project (HRAP) grid coordinate system, a polar stereographic projection true at 60°N / 105°W. The data represent the 24-hour precipitation estimates for each HRAP grid cell. </aabstract>
    <valuecount>578164822</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>33299</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>226</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>LMRFC_Data</NetworkName>
    <minx>-96.2134</minx>
    <miny>28.9833</miny>
    <maxx>-81.2691</maxx>
    <maxy>38.173</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/shalenetwork/webapp/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Shale Network</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=228</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>sxb7@psu.edu</Email>
    <phone>814-865-1619</phone>
    <organization>Shale Network</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.shalenetwork.org</orgwebsite>
    <citation>ShaleNetwork Database. DOI: 10.4211/his-data-shalenetwork</citation>
    <aabstract>The ShaleNetwork is a group of individuals working together to publish water quality and quantity data online for regions where shale gas is being exploited in the northeastern U.S.A. (www.shalenetwork.org). The ShaleNetwork database includes data generated by academic researchers, government agencies, industry representatives, nonprofit entities, watershed groups, and others; data from all entities are welcome, as long as data quality is maintained. The ShaleNetwork acts as an “honest broker” that collates datasets, publishes them in the CUAHSI HIS, and synthesizes the data into useful knowledge. To cite the database, cite the doi as doi:10.4211/his-data-shalenetwork. Papers that have been published interpreting the data are noted below. The Steering Committee of the ShaleNetwork derive from Penn State, Dickinson College, University of Pittsburgh, and the Consortium of Universities for the Advancement of Hydrologic Sciences, Inc. This group was funded originally by the National Science Foundation in October 2011 to put together the database and to run annual workshops between 2012 and 2015 (RCN-SEES funding, OCE-11-40159 to S. Brantley).  The group is seeking funding to continue the work. </aabstract>
    <valuecount>1099676</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1741</variablecount>
    <sitecount>26721</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>228</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>ShaleNetworkODM</NetworkName>
    <minx>-83.142</minx>
    <miny>29.9414</miny>
    <maxx>-72.26</maxx>
    <maxy>50.6158</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://drought.usu.edu/usbrreservoirs/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>USBR Upper Colorado River Basin Reservoir Data</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=240</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jeff.horsburgh@usu.edu</Email>
    <phone>435-797-2946</phone>
    <organization>United States Bureau of Reclamation</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.usbr.gov</orgwebsite>
    <citation>USBR, (2012), Reservoir data obtained from the USBR Upper Colorado River basin web service, United States Bureau of Reclamation</citation>
    <aabstract>This web service provides access to reservoir pool elevation, storage, inflow, and outflow data as published by the United States Bureau of Reclamation for reservoirs in the Upper Colorado River basin.  The web service retrieves data from the USBR website, formats it as WaterML, and returns it to the user.  This web service was developed by Utah State University as part of a National Integrated Droungt Information System Project sponsored by the United States Geological Survey.  </aabstract>
    <valuecount>2734340</valuecount>
    <variablecount>7</variablecount>
    <sitecount>61</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>240</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>UCRB_USBR</NetworkName>
    <minx>-112.1319</minx>
    <miny>32.54667</miny>
    <maxx>-104.3786</maxx>
    <maxy>42.24917</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://drought.usu.edu/ncdc_l1/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>NCDC Upper Colorado River Basin Precipitation</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=242</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jeff.horsburgh@usu.edu</Email>
    <phone>435-797-2946</phone>
    <organization>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA ) National Climatic Data Center (NCDC)</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/oa/ncdc.html</orgwebsite>
    <citation>NCDC, (2012), Precipitation data obtained from the NCDC WaterOneFlow web service for the Upper Colorado River basin, National Climatic Data Center</citation>
    <aabstract>This web service provides access to precipitation data for sites within or near the Upper Colorado River basin.  The web services retrieves data from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) National Climatic Data Center (NCDC), formats it as WaterML, and returns it to the user.  This web service was developed by Utah State University as part of a National Integrated Drought Information System (NIDIS) project sponsored by the United States Geological Survey.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>22985841</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>4097</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>242</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>UCRB_NCDC</NetworkName>
    <minx>-114.0214</minx>
    <miny>33.8</miny>
    <maxx>-103.8404</maxx>
    <maxy>45.0667</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://drought.usu.edu/SNODAS_HUC8/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>SNODAS HUC 8 Model Results</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=243</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jeff.horsburgh@usu.edu</Email>
    <phone>435-797-2946</phone>
    <organization>National Operational Hydrologic Remote Sensing Center</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.nohrsc.nws.gov/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>National Operational Hydrologic Remote Sensing Center. 2004. Snow Data Assimilation System (SNODAS) data products at NSIDC. Boulder, CO: National Snow and Ice Data Center. Digital media.</citation>
    <aabstract>This data set contains output from the NOAA National Weather Service's National Operational Hydrologic Remote Sensing Center (NOHRSC) SNOw Data Assimilation System (SNODAS). SNODAS is a modeling and data assimilation system developed by NOHRSC to provide the best possible estimates of snow cover and associated parameters to support hydrologic modeling and analysis. The aim of SNODAS is to provide a physically consistent framework to integrate snow data from satellite, airborne platforms, and ground stations with model estimates of snow cover (Carroll et al. 2001). SNODAS includes procedures to ingest and downscale output from the Numerical Weather Prediction (NWP) models, and to simulate snowcover using a physically based, spatially-distributed energy- and mass-balance snow model. SNODAS also includes procedures to assimilate satellite-derived, airborne, and ground-based observations of snow covered area and Snow Water Equivalent (SWE). These data are not suitable for snow fall events or totals for specific regions. For snow fall data, please see the state climatology reports for a particular state. These data are 8-digit USGS Hydrologic Unit (HUC) level summaries of snow cover, snow depth, and snow water equivalent for 8-digit HUC units within the Upper Colorado River basin.  The data were derived from gridded data sets for the continental United States at 1 km spatial resolution and 24 hour temporal resolution.  This WaterOneFlow web service was created by Utah State University as part of a National Integrated Drought Information System (NIDIS) project sponsored by the United States Geological Survey.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>1122839</valuecount>
    <variablecount>3</variablecount>
    <sitecount>100</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>243</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>UCRB_SNODAS_HUC8</NetworkName>
    <minx>-112.5113</minx>
    <miny>35.10585</miny>
    <maxx>-105.2492</maxx>
    <maxy>43.53681</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://drought.usu.edu/SNODAS_HUC10/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>SNODAS HUC 10 Model Results</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=244</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jeff.horsburgh@usu.edu</Email>
    <phone>435-797-2946</phone>
    <organization>National Operational Hydrologic Remote Sensing Center</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.nohrsc.nws.gov/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>National Operational Hydrologic Remote Sensing Center. 2004. Snow Data Assimilation System (SNODAS) data products at NSIDC. Boulder, CO: National Snow and Ice Data Center. Digital media.</citation>
    <aabstract>This data set contains output from the NOAA National Weather Service's National Operational Hydrologic Remote Sensing Center (NOHRSC) SNOw Data Assimilation System (SNODAS). SNODAS is a modeling and data assimilation system developed by NOHRSC to provide the best possible estimates of snow cover and associated parameters to support hydrologic modeling and analysis. The aim of SNODAS is to provide a physically consistent framework to integrate snow data from satellite, airborne platforms, and ground stations with model estimates of snow cover (Carroll et al. 2001). SNODAS includes procedures to ingest and downscale output from the Numerical Weather Prediction (NWP) models, and to simulate snowcover using a physically based, spatially-distributed energy- and mass-balance snow model. SNODAS also includes procedures to assimilate satellite-derived, airborne, and ground-based observations of snow covered area and Snow Water Equivalent (SWE). These data are not suitable for snow fall events or totals for specific regions. For snow fall data, please see the state climatology reports for a particular state. These data are 10-digit USGS Hydrologic Unit (HUC) level summaries of snow cover, snow depth, and snow water equivalent for 10-digit HUC units within the Upper Colorado River basin. The data were derived from gridded data sets for the continental United States at 1 km spatial resolution and 24 hour temporal resolution. This WaterOneFlow web service was created by Utah State University as part of a National Integrated Drought Information System (NIDIS) project sponsored by the United States Geological Survey.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>6935326</valuecount>
    <variablecount>3</variablecount>
    <sitecount>632</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>244</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>UCRB_SNODAS_HUC10</NetworkName>
    <minx>-112.3502</minx>
    <miny>35.44468</miny>
    <maxx>-105.455</maxx>
    <maxy>43.53138</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydro10.sdsc.edu/MeteoFR/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>DRIHM-FRANCE</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=257</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>olivier.caumont@meteo.fr</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>French Ministry of Ecology and Sustainable Development</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.vigicrues.gouv.fr/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>French Ministry of Ecology and Sustainable Development</citation>
    <aabstract>Data collected by hydrometric agencies on behalf of the French Ministry of Ecology and Sustainable Development. These are 'real-time' data that were neither controlled nor validated, and are subject to change. They do not have any official value.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>1346</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>7</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>257</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>Vigicrues Meteo FR</NetworkName>
    <minx>4.09</minx>
    <miny>43.15</miny>
    <maxx>6.453</maxx>
    <maxy>44.399</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydro.keskari.webfactional.com/index.php/default/services/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Lahti Urban Water Laboratory</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=261</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jirikadlec2@gmail.com</Email>
    <phone>(208)313-8076</phone>
    <organization>Aalto university department of environmental informatics</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://geoinformatics.aalto.fi</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Kadlec, J., Jolma, A. Lahti urban water laboratory for sustainable development.</citation>
    <aabstract>The urban water laboratory experimental site studies the impact of stormwater runoff best management practices on water quality in the lake.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>75</valuecount>
    <variablecount>2</variablecount>
    <sitecount>3</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>261</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>LUWL</NetworkName>
    <minx>25.60947</minx>
    <miny>60.99117</miny>
    <maxx>25.6508</maxx>
    <maxy>61.02018</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydro1.sci.gsfc.nasa.gov/daac-bin/his/1.0/GLDAS_NOAH_001.cgi?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>GLDAS 3-hourly Noah Data </Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=262</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>gsfc-help-disc@lists.nasa.gov</Email>
    <phone>301-614-5224</phone>
    <organization>NASA Goddard Earth Sciences (GES) Data and Information Services Center</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://disc.sci.gsfc.nasa.gov/hydrology/data-holdings</orgwebsite>
    <citation> Mitchell, K.E., D. Lohmann, P.R. Houser, E.F. Wood, J.C. Schaake, A. Robock, B.A. Cosgrove, J. Sheffield, Q. Duan, L. Luo, R.W. Higgins, R.T. Pinker, J.D. Tarpley, D.P. Lettenmaier, C.H. Marshall, J.K. Entin, M. Pan, W. Shi, V. Koren, J. Meng, B. H. Ramsay, and A.A. Bailey (2004), The multi-institution North American Land Data Assimilation System (NLDAS): Utilizing multiple GCIP products and partners in a continental distributed hydrological modeling system, J. Geophys. Res., 109, D07S90, doi:10.1029/2003JD003823.</citation>
    <aabstract>The goal of NLDAS is to construct quality-controlled, and spatially and temporally consistent, land-surface model (LSM) datasets from the best available observations and model output to support modeling activities. Specifically, this system is intended to reduce the errors in the stores of soil moisture and energy which are often present in numerical weather prediction models, and which degrade the accuracy of forecasts. NLDAS is currently running in near real-time on a 1/8th-degree grid over central North America; retrospective NLDAS datasets and simulations also extend back to January 1979. NLDAS constructs a forcing dataset from gauge-based observed precipitation data (temporally disaggregated using Stage II radar data), bias-correcting shortwave radiation, and surface meteorology reanalyses to drive several different LSMs to produce model outputs of surface fluxes, soil moisture, and snow cover. NLDAS is a collaboration project among several groups: NOAA/NCEP's Environmental Modeling Center (EMC), NASA's Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC), Princeton University, the University of Washington, the NOAA/NWS Office of Hydrological Development (OHD), and the NOAA/NCEP Climate Prediction Center (CPC). NLDAS is a core project with support from NOAA's Climate Prediction Program for the Americas (CPPA). Data from the project can be accessed from the NASA Goddard Earth Science Data and Information Services Center (GES DISC) as well as from the NCEP/EMC NLDAS website. This service provides access to NASA's North American Land Data Assimilation System (NLDAS) hourly Mosaic land surface model data.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>2147483647</valuecount>
    <variablecount>13</variablecount>
    <sitecount>241942</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>262</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>GLDAS_NOAH</NetworkName>
    <minx>-179.875</minx>
    <miny>-55.625</miny>
    <maxx>179.875</maxx>
    <maxy>83.625</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydro1.sci.gsfc.nasa.gov/daac-bin/his/1.0/NLDAS_NOAH_002.cgi?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>NLDAS Hourly NOAH Data</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=274</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>gsfc-help-disc@lists.nasa.gov</Email>
    <phone>301-614-5224</phone>
    <organization>NASA Goddard Earth Sciences (GES) Data and Information Services Center</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://disc.sci.gsfc.nasa.gov/hydrology/data-holdings</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Mitchell, K.E., D. Lohmann, P.R. Houser, E.F. Wood, J.C. Schaake, A. Robock, B.A. Cosgrove, J. Sheffield, Q. Duan, L. Luo, R.W. Higgins, R.T. Pinker, J.D. Tarpley, D.P. Lettenmaier, C.H. Marshall, J.K. Entin, M. Pan, W. Shi, V. Koren, J. Meng, B. H. Ramsay, and A.A. Bailey (2004), The multi-institution North American Land Data Assimilation System (NLDAS): Utilizing multiple GCIP products and partners in a continental distributed hydrological modeling system, J. Geophys. Res., 109, D07S90, doi:10.1029/2003JD003823.</citation>
    <aabstract>The goal of NLDAS is to construct quality-controlled, and spatially and temporally consistent, land-surface model (LSM) datasets from the best available observations and model output to support modeling activities. Specifically, this system is intended to reduce the errors in the stores of soil moisture and energy which are often present in numerical weather prediction models, and which degrade the accuracy of forecasts. NLDAS is currently running in near real-time on a 1/8th-degree grid over central North America; retrospective NLDAS datasets and simulations also extend back to January 1979. NLDAS constructs a forcing dataset from gauge-based observed precipitation data (temporally disaggregated using Stage II radar data), bias-correcting shortwave radiation, and surface meteorology reanalyses to drive several different LSMs to produce model outputs of surface fluxes, soil moisture, and snow cover. NLDAS is a collaboration project among several groups: NOAA/NCEP's Environmental Modeling Center (EMC), NASA's Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC), Princeton University, the University of Washington, the NOAA/NWS Office of Hydrological Development (OHD), and the NOAA/NCEP Climate Prediction Center (CPC). NLDAS is a core project with support from NOAA's Climate Prediction Program for the Americas (CPPA). Data from the project can be accessed from the NASA Goddard Earth Science Data and Information Services Center (GES DISC) as well as from the NCEP/EMC NLDAS website. This service provides access to NASA's North American Land Data Assimilation System (NLDAS) hourly Mosaic land surface model data.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>2147483647</valuecount>
    <variablecount>4</variablecount>
    <sitecount>103936</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>274</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>NLDAS_NOAH</NetworkName>
    <minx>-124.9375</minx>
    <miny>25.0625</miny>
    <maxx>-67.0625</maxx>
    <maxy>52.9375</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://worldwater.byu.edu/interactive/gill_lab/services/index.php/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Gill Ecosystem and Global Change Ecology Lab-BYU</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=276</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>connerlg@byu.edu</Email>
    <phone>801-422-2175</phone>
    <organization>Gill Ecosystem and Global Change Ecology Lab-BYU</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://gilllab.byu.edu</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Gill Ecosystem and Global Change Ecology Lab, Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah. </citation>
    <aabstract>These data come from a couple of different ecological/hydrological studies we have been conducting in the subalpine areas of the Wasatch Plateau and the Great Basin and Mojave Deserts. The data are divided into two sources on our HydroServer: Lafe Conner and Gill Lab. 

The data from Lafe Conner come from a snowmelt experiment where we use dust to melt snow more quickly, and compare the hydrological and ecological responses to the timing of snowmelt. These data are collected using Decagon instruments and data loggers. We are measuring soil moisture and temperature at depths of 5 and 30 cm in control and dust-treatment plots. Each experimental plot is 5 by 5 meters. For the dust treatments we apply 50 g/m2 at weekly intervals for 5 or 6 weeks starting on March 15th.     

The data from Gill lab include three rainfall manipulation experiments. The first experiment began in 2009 on the Wasatch Plateau in the upper watershed of Ephraim Canyon. In this experiment we are observing the hydrological and ecological responses to changes in the timing and amount of precipitation. There are treatments that remove 30% and 70% of rainfall, and treatments where all the rain is removed from the plot and then applied at set intervals of 1 and 3 weeks. The experiments in the Mojave and Great Basin Deserts are identical to each other and we have three rainfall treatments in each replicate: 30% reduction in rainfall, control, and 30% addition.  </aabstract>
    <valuecount>1672019</valuecount>
    <variablecount>11</variablecount>
    <sitecount>130</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>276</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>GIL_BYU</NetworkName>
    <minx>-111.4845</minx>
    <miny>39.29055</miny>
    <maxx>-111.2992</maxx>
    <maxy>40.52507</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydro10.sdsc.edu/cantho/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Can Tho University Salinity Study</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=282</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>duongvani@gmail.com</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>Can Tho University, Vietnam, Wetlands University Network</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://websrv.ctu.edu.vn/en/</orgwebsite>
    <citation />
    <aabstract>This study is conducted in conjunction with the Wetlands Universities Network Project</aabstract>
    <valuecount>2119</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>76</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>282</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>CanTho1</NetworkName>
    <minx>104.8885</minx>
    <miny>8.827816</miny>
    <maxx>106.7651</maxx>
    <maxy>10.24182</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://143.234.88.22/TarlandWaterQualityDataWS/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Tarland Catchment Water Quality Data, Scotland, UK</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=287</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>adekunle.ibiyemi@hutton.ac.uk</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>The James Hutton Institute, Aberdeen, Scotland, UK</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.hutton.ac.uk/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Data provided by
The James Hutton Institute
Cragiebuckler, Aberdeen
AB15 8QH
Scotland,UK
</citation>
    <aabstract>The data are from the river water processes and qualities monitoring sites being managed by the institute. We do not accept any liability as a result from the use of these data. Please contact us for further information.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>363509</valuecount>
    <variablecount>39</variablecount>
    <sitecount>24</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>287</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>ABHYD02</NetworkName>
    <minx>-2.895416</minx>
    <miny>57.11006</miny>
    <maxx>-2.806031</maxx>
    <maxy>57.15719</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/Wilkes/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>The Institute for Energy &amp; Environmental Research at Wilkes University</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=292</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>brian.naberezny@wilkes.edu</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>The Institute for Energy &amp; Environmental Research at Wilkes University</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://energy.wilkes.edu/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>SRBC Remote Water Quality Monitoring Network (http://www.srbc.net/). Republished by The Institute for Energy &amp; Environmental Research at Wilkes University.</citation>
    <aabstract>The present IEER database contains re-published water quality data from the Susquehanna River Basin Commission (http://www.srbc.net/).

SRBC’s Remote Water Quality Monitoring Network is guided by six primary objectives: 1. To establish a real-time monitoring network at areas of concern in the Susquehanna River Basin; network provides monitoring data to resource agencies, the regulated community and the public to allow timely response in the case of pollution incidents; 2. To establish baseline water quality conditions in targeted areas of the basin; 3. To verify whether or not the natural gas industry and/or other activities with the potential to cause pollution incidents are causing adverse impacts on local water quality; 4. To reduce the cost of data collection through the use of advanced technologies; to form collaborative partnerships to improve monitoring technology and provide educational opportunities; 5. To enhance water supply protection through source water monitoring; and 6. To be responsive to public concerns. Additional information can be found at http://mdw.srbc.net/remotewaterquality/ </aabstract>
    <valuecount>1956391</valuecount>
    <variablecount>38</variablecount>
    <sitecount>5</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>292</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>IEER at Wilkes University</NetworkName>
    <minx>-77.64986</minx>
    <miny>41.30971</miny>
    <maxx>-77.23051</maxx>
    <maxy>41.74124</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://arctic.hydrodata.org/services/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?wsdl</servURL>
    <Title>OGIMET Arctic Climate Data</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=310</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jiri.kadlec@aalto.fi</Email>
    <phone>050-573-5471</phone>
    <organization>Aalto university department of environmental sciences and OGIMET</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://geoinformatics.aalto.fi</orgwebsite>
    <citation>OGIMET daily meteorological data. www.ogimet.com</citation>
    <aabstract>GIMET global daily summary of the day (GSOD) observations from the Arctic region. Processed by OGIMET (www.ogimet.com) and re-published in WaterML format by Jiří Kadlec. Warning: This data are derived from NOAA Global Summary Of the Day. So, the summaries provided here are based on data exchanged under the World Meteorological Organization (WMO) World Weather Watch Program according to WMO Resolution 40 (Cg-XII). These data summaries and products which are available here are intended for free and unrestricted use in research, education, and other non-commercial activities</aabstract>
    <valuecount>2068581</valuecount>
    <variablecount>10</variablecount>
    <sitecount>50</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>310</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>OGIMET-ARCTIC</NetworkName>
    <minx>-73</minx>
    <miny>60</miny>
    <maxx>-13.71694</maxx>
    <maxy>83.65</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydrodata.info/chmi-h/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?wsdl</servURL>
    <Title>Hydrodata.cz Hourly Observations</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=354</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jirikadlec2@gmail.com</Email>
    <phone>385-204-2998</phone>
    <organization>Hydrodata.cz Czech data centre</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://hydrodata.cz</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Data from hydrodata.cz website collected by CHMI, Povodi Vltavy, Povodi Labe, Povodí Ohře and local early-warning systems.</citation>
    <aabstract>Snow depth, temperature, water level and discharge collected from hydrodata.cz</aabstract>
    <valuecount>130945226</valuecount>
    <variablecount>4</variablecount>
    <sitecount>1187</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>354</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>HYDRODATACZ-HR</NetworkName>
    <minx>12.1797</minx>
    <miny>48.59366</miny>
    <maxx>18.89149</maxx>
    <maxy>51.0008</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/panolaemma/webapp/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Panola Chemistry Data for EMMA</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=385</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>RHooper@cuahsi.org</Email>
    <phone>339-221-5400</phone>
    <organization>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS)</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://ga.water.usgs.gov/projects/panola/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Christophersen, N. and Hooper, R.P., 1992, Multivariate analysis of stream water quality: The use of principal components for the end-member mixing problem,Water Resour. Res., 28, 99-107.</citation>
    <aabstract>These data were used by Hooper et al  (1990) and Christophersen and Hooper (1992) in the initial development of End Member Mixing Analysis. </aabstract>
    <valuecount>6335</valuecount>
    <variablecount>7</variablecount>
    <sitecount>1</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>385</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>Panola ODM</NetworkName>
    <minx>-84.1724</minx>
    <miny>33.6318</miny>
    <maxx>-84.1724</maxx>
    <maxy>33.6318</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/SwedishMonitoringData/webapp/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Swedish Monitoring Data</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=431</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>Kevin.Bishop@slu.se</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>Swedish Agency for Marine and Water Management</organization>
    <orgwebsite>https://www.havochvatten.se/en/start.html</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Swedish Monitoring Data from the Swedish Agency for Marine and Water Management obtained via the CUAHSI Water Data Center.</citation>
    <aabstract>Chemistry, runoff, depositon and climate data from more than 200 streams throughout Sweden. </aabstract>
    <valuecount>4129674</valuecount>
    <variablecount>13</variablecount>
    <sitecount>215</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>431</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>Swedish Monitoring Data</NetworkName>
    <minx>11.27257</minx>
    <miny>55.44944</miny>
    <maxx>24.13106</maxx>
    <maxy>68.35625</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://his09.umbc.edu/BaltPub/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Baltimore, MD Photosynthetically Active Radiation (PAR)</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=451</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jncole@umbc.edu</Email>
    <phone>410-455-1765</phone>
    <organization>University of Maryland Baltimore County (UMBC)</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://cuere.umbc.edu/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Cole, J.C. and C. Welty. 2013. Photosynthetically Active Radiation (PAR) for Dead Run Sites in Baltimore MD, June 2012 – present. Data set collected by the Center for Urban Environmental Research and Education, University of Maryland, Baltimore County, Baltimore, MD, USA.   Available online (http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_services.aspx) from Consortium of Universities for the Advancement of Hydrologic Science, Inc., Boston, MA, USA. </citation>
    <aabstract>Photosynthetically Active Radiation (PAR) data have been collected at six sites in Dead Run (near Woodlawn, MD) since June 2012 by the Center for Urban Environmental Research and Education at University of Maryland, Baltimore County (http://cuere.umbc.edu) as part of NSF project CBET-0854307.  The deployed device is a Photosynthetic Light (PAR) Smart Sensor S-LIA-M003 by Onset.  The sensor measures light intensity for frequencies relevant to photosynthesis in units of µmol/m2/sec. Sensor specifications are posted at http://www.onsetcomp.com/products/sensors/s-lia-m003.   Sensors are configured to collect data at a 5-minute interval. Data are stored in a Onset Microstation Data Logger H21-002 http://www.onsetcomp.com/products/data-loggers/h21-002 and downloaded manually every 60 days.  Data are stored on a SQL server at CUERE.  The UMBC PAR sensor deployments are co-located with USGS stream gages at: 
Dead Run Franklintown (http://waterdata.usgs.gov/md/nwis/uv/?site_no=01589330), 
DR1 (http://waterdata.usgs.gov/md/nwis/uv?site_no=01589317), 
DR2 (http://waterdata.usgs.gov/md/nwis/uv?site_no=01589316), 
DR3 (http://waterdata.usgs.gov/md/nwis/uv?site_no=01589320), 
DR4 (http://waterdata.usgs.gov/md/nwis/uv?site_no=01589315), 
DR5 (http://waterdata.usgs.gov/md/nwis/uv?site_no=01589312).
</aabstract>
    <valuecount>1961376</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>6</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>451</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>Baltimore Ecosystem Study LTER</NetworkName>
    <minx>-76.74514</minx>
    <miny>39.29589</miny>
    <maxx>-76.71664</maxx>
    <maxy>39.31892</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/umassblackstone/webapp/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Upper Blackstone Water Pollution Abatement District</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=489</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>esfinn@cns.umass.edu</Email>
    <phone>413-545-5979</phone>
    <organization>University of Massachusetts Water Resources Research Center</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://wrrc.umass.edu/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Rees, Paula Sturdevant, 2012. Blackstone River Water Quality Monitoring Program Draft Report - 2012 Field Season, Water Resources Research Center, University of Massachusetts, Amherst, MA.</citation>
    <aabstract>The Upper Blackstone Water Pollution Abatement District (UBWPAD or “District”) has been conducting a long-term study of the river that includes both data collection and analysis and modeling of surface water flow and quality, conducted jointly by the University of Massachusetts (UMass Amherst) and CDM Smith, an environmental engineering firm. The project is built on earlier work conducted by the U.S Geological Survey (USGS), and has been peer reviewed by an independent technical advisory committee (TAC). The District has been proactive about maintaining a routine water quality monitoring program to track the impacts of the plant upgrades on river quality. In 2012, UMass conducted a water quality monitoring program along the mainstem of the Blackstone River. The objective of the program was to collect data to help assess response of the river to reduced nutrient concentrations in the UBWPAD effluent. Sampling was conducted from April through November at Blackstone River main stem locations. The study included monthly water quality sampling for nutrients, bi-weekly monitoring for chlorophyll-a, and a visual assessment of algal blooms and macrophyte growth. Three Rhode Island sites were co-sampled with the Narragansett Bay Commission (NBC). </aabstract>
    <valuecount>2696</valuecount>
    <variablecount>20</variablecount>
    <sitecount>22</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>489</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>UBWPAD</NetworkName>
    <minx>-71.8069</minx>
    <miny>41.87696</miny>
    <maxx>-71.38193</maxx>
    <maxy>42.2421</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://webh2o.net/site/wof/cuahsi_1_1.asmx</servURL>
    <Title>WebH2O myObservatory Data Publication Service</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=499</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>chris.michaelis@webh2o.net</Email>
    <phone>208-793-0183</phone>
    <organization>WebH2O, LLC</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.my-observatory.com</orgwebsite>
    <citation />
    <aabstract />
    <valuecount>260</valuecount>
    <variablecount>20</variablecount>
    <sitecount>20</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>499</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>WebH2O</NetworkName>
    <minx>-122.42</minx>
    <miny>37.55</miny>
    <maxx>-121.99</maxx>
    <maxy>38.02</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://okeanos.limnology.wisc.edu/GLEON/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Global Lakes Ecological Observatory Network</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=2502</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>cgries@wisc.edu</Email>
    <phone>(608)890-3446</phone>
    <organization>Global Lakes Ecological Observatory Network</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://gleon.org</orgwebsite>
    <citation />
    <aabstract />
    <valuecount>212779926</valuecount>
    <variablecount>42</variablecount>
    <sitecount>352</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>2502</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>GLEON</NetworkName>
    <minx>-89.71224</minx>
    <miny>43.0583</miny>
    <maxx>-89.40134</maxx>
    <maxy>46.04123</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/GLEON_Auburn/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Lake Auburn, Maine, USA. Instrumented Buoy.</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=3552</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>hewing@bates.edu</Email>
    <phone>207-786-8315</phone>
    <organization>Bates College</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.bates.edu</orgwebsite>
    <citation />
    <aabstract />
    <valuecount>359583</valuecount>
    <variablecount>4</variablecount>
    <sitecount>1</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>3552</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>GLEON_Auburn</NetworkName>
    <minx>-70.2522</minx>
    <miny>44.13838</miny>
    <maxx>-70.2522</maxx>
    <maxy>44.13838</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/GLEON_Dorset/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL </servURL>
    <Title>Dorset Environmental Science Centre</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=3555</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>Jim.Rusak@ontario.ca</Email>
    <phone>705-766-0659</phone>
    <organization>Dorset Environmental Science Centre</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://desc.ca</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Data provided by the Dorset Environmental Science Centre of the Ontario Ministry of the Environment</citation>
    <aabstract>Focusing on headwater lakes and streams near Dorset, Ontario, this program gathers chemical, physical and biological data to investigate long-term patterns and processes in aquatic ecosystems. A watershed scale approach is used to investigate the effects of multiple stressors, including climate change, on water quality and quantity in Ontario’s inland aquatic ecosystems and sustain the functions and services that these systems provide.
Currently CUAHSI is hosting 10-minute data, for a wide variety of parameters, from the Dorset Environmental Science Centre's automated sensing platform on Harp Lake in the Muskoka Region of Ontario.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>768731</valuecount>
    <variablecount>16</variablecount>
    <sitecount>1</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>3555</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>GLEON_Dorset</NetworkName>
    <minx>-79.13396</minx>
    <miny>45.37999</miny>
    <maxx>-79.13396</maxx>
    <maxy>45.37999</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://data.iutahepscor.org/ProvoRiverWOF/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Provo River GAMUT, Utah, USA</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=3567</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>amber.jones@usu.edu</Email>
    <phone>(435) 797-7147</phone>
    <organization>Brigham Young University, iUTAH EPSCoR</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://gamut.iutahepscor.org</orgwebsite>
    <citation>iUTAH GAMUT Working Group. (2014), GAMUT Ecohydrologic Data, 1.0, iUTAH Modeling and Data Federation, http://data.iutahepscor.org</citation>
    <aabstract>iUTAH researchers have developed and deployed an ecohydrologic observatory to study water in ‘Gradients Along Mountain to Urban Transitions’ (GAMUT). The GAMUT Network measures aspects of climate, hydrology, and water quality along a mountain-to-urban gradient in three watersheds that share common water sources (winter-derived precipitation) but differ in the human and biophysical nature of land-use transitions. GAMUT includes state-of-the-art sensors at aquatic and terrestrial sites for real-time monitoring of common meteorological variables, snow accumulation and melt, soil moisture, surface water flow, and surface water quality.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>36965762</valuecount>
    <variablecount>120</variablecount>
    <sitecount>18</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>3567</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>Provo River GAMUT</NetworkName>
    <minx>-111.4626</minx>
    <miny>40.46691</miny>
    <maxx>-110.9483</maxx>
    <maxy>40.67811</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://www.aquagis.pt/timeseries/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>AquaGIS AmbiSIG</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=3569</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>VFerreira@ambisig.pt</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>AmbiSIG SA</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.ambisig.com/site/frontoffice/default.aspx</orgwebsite>
    <citation>AquaGIS-Robotic autonomous platform for surface water monitoring</citation>
    <aabstract>The development of the AquaGIS robotic platform is being done in the scope of a research and development project that aims the construction of an autonomous catamaran vessel for surface water monitoring. The vessel was designed to respond to the European Water Framework Directive (WFD) monitoring programms demands.
 
Project funded by the Portuguese Innovation Agency (ANI) through EU (European Regional Development Fund) and QREN.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>3751069</valuecount>
    <variablecount>22</variablecount>
    <sitecount>1</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>3569</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>aquagis_ambisig</NetworkName>
    <minx>-9.14358</minx>
    <miny>38.76046</miny>
    <maxx>-9.14358</maxx>
    <maxy>38.76046</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://sensor.nevada.edu/Services/Ashpan/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Lassen National Forest</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=4561</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>rmg55@cornell.edu</Email>
    <phone>720-724-7156</phone>
    <organization>University of Nevada Reno</organization>
    <orgwebsite>https://www.unr.edu/</orgwebsite>
    <citation />
    <aabstract>Fuel-reduction treatments are commonly employed throughout the western United States to improve forest health and/or decrease the risk of wildland fires. Periods of prolonged drought and high temperatures increase both the risk of wildland fires and the stress on water resources. Forest managers may mitigate the risk of wildland fires by increasing fuel-reduction treatments but the subsequent effect on forest hydrology and water resources is not well understood. Of particularly interest to water resources is the effect on snow pack accumulation and melt timing, which is impacted by forest cover. As part of a Comprehensive Forest Landscape Restoration Program (CFLRP), four sites were selected in the Hat Creek Basin of Lassen National Forest to study the hydrologic effects of two common fuel-reduction strategies, forest thinning and group selection. During the 2013/2014 winter, California experienced a significant drought, including a near-absence of continuous snow cover. Therefore, the effect on snow accumulation and melt timing during the 13/14 and 14/15 winter was not directly measured. However, significant deviations in solar radiation, wind speed, and solar moisture were observed in the data, suggesting fuel reduction treatments will have a tangible effect of snow pack and forest hydrology. Further work to examine the relationship between forest cover, fuel-treatments, and basin hydrology includes the analysis of historic stream flow data and the development of a hydro-ecological model for the basin.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>1794122</valuecount>
    <variablecount>15</variablecount>
    <sitecount>4</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>4561</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>lnf_hydro</NetworkName>
    <minx>-121.5506</minx>
    <miny>40.6</miny>
    <maxx>-121.546</maxx>
    <maxy>40.6024</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/cedarriver/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Cedar River Watershed Forest Snow Observations</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=4569</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jdlund@uw.edu</Email>
    <phone>206-685-7594</phone>
    <organization>University of Washington</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://depts.washington.edu/mtnhydr/data/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Dickerson-Lange, S.E., Lutz, J.A., Gersonde, R., Martin, K.A., Forsyth, J., and J.D. Lundquist (2015, in preparation for Water Resources Research), Observations of distributed snow depth and snow duration within diverse forest structures in a maritime mountain watershed
</citation>
    <aabstract>Spatially distributed snow depth and snow duration data were collected over two to four snow seasons during water years 2011-2014 in experimental forest plots within the Cedar River Municipal Watershed, 50 km east of Seattle, Washington, USA.  These 40 m × 40 m forest plots, situated on the western slope of the Cascade Range, include un-thinned second-growth coniferous forest as control treatments, variable density thinned forests, forest gaps in which a 20 m diameter (approximately equivalent to one tree height) gap was cut in the middle of each plot, and old growth forest.   

The complete dataset includes snow depth observations from manual snow courses, distributed snow duration observations from ground temperature sensors and time-lapse cameras, meteorological data collected at two open locations and three forested locations, and forest canopy data from airborne light detection and ranging (LiDAR) data and hemispherical photographs.  Currently archived via CUAHSI HIS are the FOC ground temperature data, from which distributed snow presence can be inferred, from water year 2011.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>2726625</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>825</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>4569</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>CedarRiver</NetworkName>
    <minx>-121.5427</minx>
    <miny>47.3411</miny>
    <maxx>-121.5381</maxx>
    <maxy>47.34323</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/nceiww2/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>World War II Era Summary of the Day Data</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5573</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>help@cuahsi.org</Email>
    <phone>339-221-5400</phone>
    <organization>NOAA National Centers for Environmental Information</organization>
    <orgwebsite>https://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>World War II Era Summary of the Day data from NOAA's National Centers for Environmental Information. Accessed via the CUAHSI HIS Central. Original data available: https://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/data-access/land-based-station-data/land-based-datasets/world-war-ii-era-data</citation>
    <aabstract>In commemoration of the 50th anniversary of the end of World War II and in honor of those who served, NOAA's National Centers for Environmental Information provides access to World War II Era Summary of the Day data. The actual period of data availability varies depending upon the station's activity, but many stations in the European and Pacific areas of operation are included. Data sets, which include daily precipitation and temperature from around the world (January 1, 1940 through December 31, 1945), were downloaded by CUAHSI staff, reformatted, and uploaded to CUAHSI's Cloud HydroServer. For more information about the World War II Summary of the Day data see the link to the original data on this page.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>476052</valuecount>
    <variablecount>4</variablecount>
    <sitecount>159</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5573</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>NCEIWW2</NetworkName>
    <minx>-175.1333</minx>
    <miny>-27.62972</miny>
    <maxx>177.45</maxx>
    <maxy>67.01667</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/SKC/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Milltown Dam Area Surface Water and Groundwater Observations</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5575</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>antony_berthelote@skc.edu</Email>
    <phone>(406) 275-4080</phone>
    <organization>Salish Kootenai College</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://naturalresources.skc.edu/hydrology/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Milltown Dam Area Surface Water and Groundwater Observations. Downloaded [Date downloaded] via the CUAHSI Water Data Center.</citation>
    <aabstract>Surface water gage height and groundwater depth measurements near the Milltown Dam site in Montana, USA. </aabstract>
    <valuecount>35719</valuecount>
    <variablecount>2</variablecount>
    <sitecount>213</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5575</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>SKC_Milltown</NetworkName>
    <minx>-113.9704</minx>
    <miny>46.81139</miny>
    <maxx>-113.8066</maxx>
    <maxy>46.88915</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/MWRA/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Boston Harbor and Massachusetts Bay Water Resources Authority</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5586</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>Help@cuahsi.org</Email>
    <phone>339-221-5400</phone>
    <organization>Massachusetts Water Resources Authority</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.mwra.state.ma.us/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>These data have not yet been published in the primary scientific literature and are the product of work by a number of scientists, many of whom have papers in preparation. Therefore, these data must not be used for publication without consulting first with MWRA's Environmental Quality Department at web.enquad@mwra.state.ma.us (or phone: 617-788-4941). Please convey this information to all who use the data.</citation>
    <aabstract>Boston Harbor encompasses nearly 50 square miles and is an estuary, where fresh water from tributary rivers mix with the salt water of Massachusetts Bay. The Massachusetts Water Resources Authority (MWRA) monitors water quality at more than 50 locations in Boston Harbor. Measurements are also made in the Charles, Mystic, and Neponset rivers. The monitoring program is designed to monitor the impacts of combined sewer overflows (CSOs) on the Harbor and rivers. The MWRA has been monitoring water quality in Boston Harbor and its tributary rivers since 1989. Collecting long-term water quality data helps to identify changes in water quality over time. The CUAHSI staff downloaded this data set from the MRWA's website, reformatted the metadata, and uploaded the data to CUAHSI's data hosting service, HydroPortal.
</aabstract>
    <valuecount>370726</valuecount>
    <variablecount>20</variablecount>
    <sitecount>51</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5586</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>MWRA</NetworkName>
    <minx>-71.19139</minx>
    <miny>42.27075</miny>
    <maxx>-70.89883</maxx>
    <maxy>42.41641</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://190.166.251.50:17500/hydroserver/index.php/default/services/cuahsi_1_1.asmx</servURL>
    <Title>Instituto Nacional de Recursos Hidráulicos Services</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5588</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>ranovalles@gmail.com</Email>
    <phone>829-715-2202</phone>
    <organization>Instituto Nacional de Recursos Hidráulicos</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.indrhi.gob.do/</orgwebsite>
    <citation />
    <aabstract />
    <valuecount>9272743</valuecount>
    <variablecount>64</variablecount>
    <sitecount>659</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5588</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>INDRHI_Services</NetworkName>
    <minx>-112.3209</minx>
    <miny>17.783</miny>
    <maxx>-68.317</maxx>
    <maxy>40.61395</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/GLEON_LakeAnnie/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Lake Annie Instrumented Buoy, Venus FL</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5594</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>ArchboldDataManager@gmail.com</Email>
    <phone>863-465-2571</phone>
    <organization>Archbold Biological Station</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.archbold-station.org/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Archbold Biological Station.  (2015). Lake Annie_Florida_15 minute buoy and lake level data_RawFlagged [Data set]. 
</citation>
    <aabstract>The GLEON_LakeAnnie Buoy was envisioned by Evelyn Gaiser (FIU) and Hilary Swain (Archbold Biological Station) in 2008, after Tim Kratz (Northern Lakes LTER) recommended Archbold add a buoy to complement the monthly lake data collection that started in 1983.  The buoy was an EMB-375 YSI buoy with a selection of sensors and instruments including a YSI sonde, thermistor chain, and LICOR PAR, as recommended by GLEON. With assistance of GLEON scientists the buoy was deployed in February 2008, in the center of the lake, together with a pressure gauge (water level) and rain gauge at the Lake Annie dock. New sensors have been added over time (micrometeorology). Many original and subsequent sensors have been replaced over time. The cost of the buoy, sensor replacement, and annual maintenance costs have been supported by Archbold Biological Station. The buoy has been maintained by Archbold technicians, especially Earl Keel, as well as Hilary Swain and Evelyn Gaiser. Datalogger programming and communications were completed by Earl Keel. Data collection began in February 2008 and the buoy has been deployed continuously since then, apart from an annual maintenance of ~2-3 days. There have been periods when different sensors failed and had to be replaced, resulting in several extended interruptions in data. Data are streamed via a wireless radio network every 15 minutes to the main buildings at Archbold, and real time data are available on the Archbold website (http://www.archbold-station.org/data/techview/index.html). Data QAQC includes systematic automated procedures (range, step, persistence) and intermittent manual review. Data are archived in an MS SQL database at Archbold for use within the GLEON network and beyond. During 2008-2015 there were 36 requests for Lake Annie buoy data and more than 11 publications (www.gleon.org).

This specific dataset consists of raw 15 minute data from the buoy, dock, and nearby weather station that have not been manually QC’ed. Data has been run through an automated flagging process to check for step, range, and persistence.  These data have not been gap-filled for missing timestamps. Please contact us for monthly calibration data. </aabstract>
    <valuecount>13271525</valuecount>
    <variablecount>29</variablecount>
    <sitecount>28</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5594</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>GLEON_LakeAnnie</NetworkName>
    <minx>-81.352</minx>
    <miny>27.2077</miny>
    <maxx>-81.34906</maxx>
    <maxy>27.21</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/MAAERI/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Mongolian-American Aquatic Ecology Research Initiative</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5595</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>olaf.p.jensen@gmail.com</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>Mongolian-American Aquatic Ecology Research Initiative</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://maaeri.weebly.com/</orgwebsite>
    <citation />
    <aabstract>Daily water temperature records (Celsius) for lake Hövsgöl and associated Eg, Uur, and Selenge Rivers in North Central Mongolia.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>727307</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>18</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5595</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>MAAERI</NetworkName>
    <minx>100.178</minx>
    <miny>49.34919</miny>
    <maxx>103.6416</maxx>
    <maxy>51.30601</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://rths.us:8088/reon/soap/cuahsi_1_1</servURL>
    <Title>River and Estuary Observatory Network</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5574</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>rnnelson@clarkson.edu</Email>
    <phone>315-261-2170</phone>
    <organization>Clarkson University's Beacon Institute</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.bire.org</orgwebsite>
    <citation>
The River and Estuary Observatory Network, a project of Clarkson University's Beacon Institute.</citation>
    <aabstract>REON is a collection of observations made by fixed proprietary instrumentation, a mobile tow package, and two commercial riverbed-mounted ADCPs.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>81964881</valuecount>
    <variablecount>44</variablecount>
    <sitecount>52</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5574</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>REON</NetworkName>
    <minx>-75.108</minx>
    <miny>41.04303</miny>
    <maxx>-73.5772</maxx>
    <maxy>44.9793</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydrodata.info/ghcn/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>GHCN Daily Climate Data</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=229</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>kadljiri@isu.edu</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>Idaho State University</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://gsl.geology.isu.edu</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Peterson, Thomas C. and Russell S. Vose (1997). "An overview of the Global Historical Climatology Network temperature data base". Bulletin of the American Meteorological Society 78 (12): 2837–2849.</citation>
    <aabstract>The Global Historical Climate Network (GHCN) provides quality-controlled precipitation and temperature time series data. The goal of this web service is to make the GHCN precipitation data available through the CUAHSI Hydrologic Information system.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>793463149</valuecount>
    <variablecount>4</variablecount>
    <sitecount>27373</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>229</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>GHCN</NetworkName>
    <minx>-178.03</minx>
    <miny>-34.48</miny>
    <maxx>179.28</maxx>
    <maxy>71.28</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://icewater.boisestate.edu/pmrw2dataservices/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Panola Mountain Research Watershed, Georgia</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=174</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>nepeters@usgs.gov</Email>
    <phone>770-903-9145</phone>
    <organization>U.S. Geological Survey, Georgia Water Science Center</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://ga.water.usgs.gov/projects/panola/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>USGS Georgia Water Science Center, Environmental Investigations and Research Section, Panola Mountain Watershed Research Group
</citation>
    <aabstract>Research Data Collection for Panola Mountain Research Watershed, since 1985.  U.S. Geological Survey, Georgia Dept of Natural Resources and WEBB Program Cooperators, project number 2503-0021S

</aabstract>
    <valuecount>7958239</valuecount>
    <variablecount>2</variablecount>
    <sitecount>2</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>174</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>ODMPMRW2</NetworkName>
    <minx>-84.17332</minx>
    <miny>33.62986</miny>
    <maxx>-84.17242</maxx>
    <maxy>33.63176</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://143.234.88.22/nwisdata/cuahsi_1_1.asmx</servURL>
    <Title>National Waters Inventory for Scotland (NWIS) 2012-2014 data</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5597</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>adekunle.ibiyemi@hutton.ac.uk</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>The James Hutton Institute, Aberdeen, Scotland, UK</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.hutton.ac.uk/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>National Waters Inventory Scotland (NWIS) 2012-2014 data, 2015. The James Hutton Institute, Aberdeen, Scotland.</citation>
    <aabstract>The National Waters Inventory for Scotland (NWIS) project consists of data from over 100 surface waters and groundwater gathered over a 2 year period. Data are on isotopic, organic and microbial characterisations of the waters. The samples were collected by the Scottish Environment Protection Agency (SEPA) and analysis mostly done in analytical laboratory of the James Hutton Institute, Aberdeen, Scotland, UK. The primary purposes of collecting the data include:to show the spatio-temporal variability of dissolved organic matter in the aquatic environment,to distinguish source provenance and transport processes within the natural ecosystem and to  show Faecal Indicator Organism (FIOs) concentrations in relation to catchment characteristics.  </aabstract>
    <valuecount>136887</valuecount>
    <variablecount>223</variablecount>
    <sitecount>98</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5597</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>NWIS</NetworkName>
    <minx>-5.434422</minx>
    <miny>54.85587</miny>
    <maxx>-1.833847</maxx>
    <maxy>58.58483</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/nevados/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Los Nevados</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5606</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>Help@cuahsi.org</Email>
    <phone>339-221-5400</phone>
    <organization>Escuela de Ingenieria de Antioquia </organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.eia.edu.co</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Los Nevados Observatory. Accessed via the CUAHSI Water Data Center.</citation>
    <aabstract>This data set has been created by the Escuela de Ingenieria de Antioquia. As part of a working group in the Global Network of Mountain Observatories (GNOMO), CUAHSI staff formatted metadata and re-published the data using CUAHSI's Cloud HydroServer.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>3945600</valuecount>
    <variablecount>3</variablecount>
    <sitecount>20</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5606</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>Nevados</NetworkName>
    <minx>-75.53911</minx>
    <miny>4.8197</miny>
    <maxx>-75.35194</maxx>
    <maxy>4.982278</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/Ramsar_atacama/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Humedales RAMSAR Atacama</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5607</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email />
    <phone />
    <organization>Ministerio del Medio Ambiente (MMA), Región de Atacama, Chile</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://portal.mma.gob.cl/region-de-atacama/</orgwebsite>
    <citation />
    <aabstract />
    <valuecount>142273</valuecount>
    <variablecount>17</variablecount>
    <sitecount>7</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5607</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>MMA_Atacama</NetworkName>
    <minx>-69.17414</minx>
    <miny>-27.46561</miny>
    <maxx>-68.97495</maxx>
    <maxy>-26.84056</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydro10.sdsc.edu/RHMSS1/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>RHMSS</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=259</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>ljiljana.dekic@hidmet.gov.rs</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>Republic Hydrometeorological Service of Serbia</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.hidmet.gov.rs</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Republic Hydrometeorological Service of SerbiaUse</citation>
    <aabstract>Data observed in national hydrological network</aabstract>
    <valuecount>31</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>1</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>259</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>RHMSS1</NetworkName>
    <minx>19.2739</minx>
    <miny>44.63273</miny>
    <maxx>19.2739</maxx>
    <maxy>44.63273</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/KStateWeather/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Kansas State University Daily Weather Data</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=269</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>auvenshi@ksu.edu</Email>
    <phone>785-532-5862</phone>
    <organization>Kansas State University</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.ksre.ksu.edu/wdl/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Kansas Weather Data Library. 2012.</citation>
    <aabstract>Daily weather data are collected at 14 stations operated by Kansas State University Research and Extension.  Data include maximum air temperature, minimum air temperature, total precipitation, average relative humidity, average wind speed, and solar radiation.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>800614</valuecount>
    <variablecount>6</variablecount>
    <sitecount>14</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>269</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>Kansas Weather Data</NetworkName>
    <minx>-101.775</minx>
    <miny>37.369</miny>
    <maxx>-95.248</maxx>
    <maxy>39.829</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydrodb.uta.edu/USACE_Data/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>USACE Hourly Reservoir Discharges values </Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=227</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>mcenery@uta.edu</Email>
    <phone>(817)272-0234</phone>
    <organization>US Army Crops of Engineers</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.usace.army.mil</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Hydrologic data from NWIS-USACE</citation>
    <aabstract>Hourly Reservoir Discharges Provided by Ft Worth Reservoir Control Branch USACE.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>178406</valuecount>
    <variablecount>1</variablecount>
    <sitecount>22</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>227</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>USACE_Data</NetworkName>
    <minx>-98.48583</minx>
    <miny>29.86861</miny>
    <maxx>-94.10583</maxx>
    <maxy>33.35528</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>https://hisprod.rtnccad.epa.gov/prod/CUAHSI_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>EPA_Lake_Harsha</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5578</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>simon.michelle@epa.gov</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>US EPA</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www2.epa.gov/aboutepa/about-national-risk-management-research-laboratory-nrmrl</orgwebsite>
    <citation>EPA Harsha Lake Project</citation>
    <aabstract />
    <valuecount>16375</valuecount>
    <variablecount>9</variablecount>
    <sitecount>173</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5578</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>EPA_Lake_Harsha_Data</NetworkName>
    <minx>-84.2975</minx>
    <miny>38.96139</miny>
    <maxx>-83.6825</maxx>
    <maxy>39.34917</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/czo_catalina/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Catalina-Jemez CZO - Santa Catalina Mountains </Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=177</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>patroch@hwr.arizona.edu</Email>
    <phone>520-626-1277</phone>
    <organization>University of Arizona</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://criticalzone.org/catalina-jemez/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Logistical support and/or data were provided by the NSF-supported Jemez River Basin and Santa Catalina Mountains Critical Zone Observatory under the NSF EAR-0724958</citation>
    <aabstract>This data service provides data collected from Santa Catalina Mountains sites.
We are developing an interdisciplinary observatory in the southwestern US that will improve our fundamental understanding of the function, structure and co-evolution of biota, soils, and landforms that comprise the Critical Zone (CZ). The observatory is designed as a natural laboratory for the earth science community to test hypotheses related to CZ function in relation to climatic and water cycle variation. We posit that CZ systems organize and evolve in response to open system fluxes of energy and mass that can be quantified at point to watershed scales. These fluxes include meteoric CZ inputs of radiation, water, and carbon that are modulated by surficial biota to produce fluids and biogeochemical components that undergo biotic and abiotic transformation during gradient-driven transport. We hypothesize that the coupling of physical, chemical and biological processes is related specifically and predictably to the timing and magnitude of these fluxes. Therefore, our CZ Observatory (CZO) is designed to examine the impacts of space-time variability in energy and water flux on coupled CZ processes along two well-constrained climate gradients. The first is on rhyolitic parent material in the Jemez River Basin of northern New Mexico (JRB) and the second is on granite and schist bedrock within the Santa Catalina Mountains in southern Arizona (SCM). Measurement, modeling, and experimentation at sites that vary in parent rock, elevation, aspect, slope, soil development, and vegetation will enable quantification of the feedbacks between energy and mass fluxes (driven by chemical and physical gradients) and measured components of CZ structure. Our team has developed an iterative modeling and measurement strategy, and a management structure that fosters integration among disciplines. The JRB-SCM CZO is organized around broad questions that require an integrated, multi-disciplinary approach including the following two: How does variability in energy input and related mass flux influence CZ structure and function? How do feedbacks between landscape evolution and the cycling of water and carbon alter short- and long-term CZ development? To identify the couplings among physical, chemical, and biological processes, our research integrates four crosscutting science themes that are both multi-disciplinary and multi-scale: Ecohydrology and Hydrologic Partitioning, Subsurface Biogeochemistry, Landscape Evolution and Surface Water Dynamics. We are employing an integrated process-based modeling approach to (i) identify optimal sites for measuring structure and process, (ii) refine hypotheses developed through field-based observation and measurements, (iii) explore feedbacks and emergent system behaviors, and (iv) develop transfer functions that can be used to relate system behavior across scales and modes of observation. Discoveries made at the JRB-SCM CZO will improve our ability to predict CZ response to changes in climate and land cover, which is immediately useful to regional resource managers and will ultimately inform broader-scale decision making. We coordinate closely with other CZOs to support data collection, storage, and dissemination. Our education and outreach activities are built upon other highly effective educational efforts developed and led at UA. We are developing a range of products and activities for K-16 students, the general public, and stakeholders, including summer Observatory field experiences for local high school and undergraduate students, graduate courses, and field camps in earth science, as well as coordination of related efforts by other science centers active in the region. We invite new investigators throughout the global earth sciences community to conduct novel and collaborative research at the JRB-SCM CZO.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>6748694</valuecount>
    <variablecount>10</variablecount>
    <sitecount>25</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>177</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>czo_catalina</NetworkName>
    <minx>-110.8405</minx>
    <miny>32.4261</miny>
    <maxx>-110.7399</maxx>
    <maxy>32.55995</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://worldwater.byu.edu/app/index.php/rushvalley/services/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Rush Valley Database</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=4559</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>brynstclair@yahoo.com</Email>
    <phone>801-471-9166</phone>
    <organization>BYU</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://byu.edu</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Gill, R (2014), Rush Valley, http://www.worldwater.byu.edu/interactive/app/application/config/installations/, Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah. (Updated regularly.)</citation>
    <aabstract />
    <valuecount>3570750</valuecount>
    <variablecount>26</variablecount>
    <sitecount>158</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>4559</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>RushValley</NetworkName>
    <minx>-112.3058</minx>
    <miny>40.08992</miny>
    <maxx>-112.3043</maxx>
    <maxy>40.0919</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/urbanwaterapi/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Southwest Pennsylvania Urban Waters</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=4562</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>damonweiss@ethoscollaborative.com</Email>
    <phone>412-266-2492</phone>
    <organization>Ethos Collaborative</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.ethoscollaborative.com</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Various sources were used to compile this data.  Please refer to the detailed metadata, provided within the CUAHSI database.</citation>
    <aabstract>This project is funded by a grant from the Allegheny County Conservation District, and is intended to pull together water-related data from various sources, published for the Southwest Pennsylvania region.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>5647</valuecount>
    <variablecount>12</variablecount>
    <sitecount>51</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>4562</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>urbanwaterapi</NetworkName>
    <minx>-80.25711</minx>
    <miny>39.7416</miny>
    <maxx>-79.81198</maxx>
    <maxy>40.53338</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/sagehencreek/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Sagehen Creek Field Station</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5590</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>Help@cuahsi.org</Email>
    <phone>339-221-5400</phone>
    <organization>University of California, Berkeley</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://sagehen.berkeley.edu/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>Sagehen Creek Field Station Data. Accessed via the CUAHSI Water Data Center. Original data available: http://www.wrcc.dri.edu/cgi-bin/rawMAIN.pl?casagh</citation>
    <aabstract>This data set has been created by the Sagehen Creek Field Station. As part of a working group in the Global Network of Mountain Observatories (GNOMO), CUAHSI staff downloaded these data from the Western Regional Climate Center, formatted metadata, and re-published the data using CUAHSI's Cloud HydroServer. </aabstract>
    <valuecount>107023</valuecount>
    <variablecount>27</variablecount>
    <sitecount>1</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5590</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>SagehenCreek</NetworkName>
    <minx>-120.2369</minx>
    <miny>39.4325</miny>
    <maxx>-120.2369</maxx>
    <maxy>39.4325</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://nmhis.unm.edu/RGET/cuahsi_1_0.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Rio-ET: Evapotranspiration Studies in the Middle Rio Grande</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=152</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>jcoonrod@unm.edu</Email>
    <phone>505-277-3233</phone>
    <organization>University of New Mexico</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://bosque.unm.edu/</orgwebsite>
    <citation>J. Cleverly, C. Dahm, J. Coonrod, K. Vanderbilt, 1999-2008, Evapotranspiration tower and well data, Rio-ET: Evapotranspiration Studies in the Middle Rio Grande, University of New Mexico</citation>
    <aabstract>Restoration efforts that remove non-native understory vegetation or dense monotypic stands of non-native vegetation from riparian zones (the bosque) are designed to reduce consumption of water. Quantification of the response of evapotranspiration (ET) and water table depths to non-native understory removal or to eradication of dense stands of non-native species like salt cedar or Russian olive is needed to provide defensible estimates of potential water-savings from restoration activities. In addition to restoration assessment, it is also important to monitor the effects the increasing roles of fire and post-burn management have on ET and water tables. We monitored the ET and water table responses of a site with understory removed (Albuquerque South Valley). 
</aabstract>
    <valuecount>31485802</valuecount>
    <variablecount>100</variablecount>
    <sitecount>8</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>152</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>RioGrandeET</NetworkName>
    <minx>-107.0394</minx>
    <miny>33.77303</miny>
    <maxx>-106.6828</maxx>
    <maxy>34.95871</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/GlobalRiversObservatory/webapp/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Global Rivers Observatory</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=3534</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>bpeucker@whoi.edu</Email>
    <phone>508-289-2518</phone>
    <organization>The Global Rivers Observatory</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.globalrivers.org/</orgwebsite>
    <citation />
    <aabstract>This is a prototype data service setup by CUAHSI staff for the Global Rivers Observatory scientists so that they can evaluate the use of HIS. Data and metadata are subject to change without notice.

Scientists from the Woods Hole Research Center and the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution have joined with partners from around the world to investigate river chemistry in Earth’s most significant river systems. Now active in 18 watersheds around the world – with the goal of expanding to several more – the Global Rivers Observatory is measuring the chemical composition of rivers near their mouths where they empty into the ocean.
	
The Global Rivers Observatory is advancing understanding of how climate change, deforestation, and other disturbances are impacting river chemistry and land-ocean linkages. This knowledge is vital for tracking the health of Earth’s watersheds and for predicting how Earth’s water and chemical cycles will change in the future. As the human population approaches 9 billion people over the coming decades, this understanding will be essential as vast numbers of people that are dependent on the services rivers provide struggle to adapt to rapidly changing conditions.</aabstract>
    <valuecount>1060</valuecount>
    <variablecount>32</variablecount>
    <sitecount>44</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>3534</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>GlobalRiversObservatory</NetworkName>
    <minx>-124.3768</minx>
    <miny>49.1722</miny>
    <maxx>-118.6027</maxx>
    <maxy>54.42168</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
  <ServiceInfo>
    <servURL>http://hydroportal.cuahsi.org/mwdis/cuahsi_1_1.asmx?WSDL</servURL>
    <Title>Mason Water Data Information System (MWDIS)</Title>
    <ServiceDescriptionURL>http://hiscentral.cuahsi.org/pub_network.aspx?n=5572</ServiceDescriptionURL>
    <Email>cferrei3@gmu.edu</Email>
    <phone />
    <organization>George Mason University</organization>
    <orgwebsite>http://www.mwdis.org/Extra</orgwebsite>
    <citation>(1)
Anne-Eleonore Paquier, Jana Haddad, Seth Lawler, Celso M. Ferreira, Ferreira's Flood Hazard Research Lab, George Mason University, Project: "Quantifying storm surge attenuation by wetlands, Wetlands and Coastal Resilience: Quantifying the power of nature to reduce storm surge," 2015-2016.</citation>
    <aabstract>The Mason Water Data Information System (MWDIS) is a platform designed to share water data collected by researchers at George Mason University. Our goal is to encourage water data sharing and to provide an internet-based system to facilitate water data publishing for the Mason research community.

PROJECT 1:
Quantifying Storm Surge Attenuation by Wetlands.

PROJECT 2:
Mason Educational Watershed</aabstract>
    <valuecount>41462</valuecount>
    <variablecount>5</variablecount>
    <sitecount>7</sitecount>
    <ServiceID>5572</ServiceID>
    <NetworkName>MWDIS</NetworkName>
    <minx>-77.30632</minx>
    <miny>37.11937</miny>
    <maxx>-75.9634</maxx>
    <maxy>38.82735</maxy>
    <serviceStatus />
  </ServiceInfo>
</ArrayOfServiceInfo>